<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-02T02:40:57+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Balmenach 2004 Hidden Spirits 13 years 51.2% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-balmenach-2004-hidden-spirits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Balmenach 2004 Hidden Spirits 13 years 51.2% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/balmenach-2004-hidden-spirits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-balmenach-2004-hidden-spirits.html">&lt;p&gt;An honest little exbourbon malt from Hidden Spirits, one of my favourite bottlers. From a rather obscure distillery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw, amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Tropical fruits! Pawpaw, rockmelon, mango. Very clear. Cinnamon sticks from afar. Fennel and light sweetness. Passionfruit sorbet. Lemon sherbet. Lemon zest. Fresh woodiness, almost wet, like trees after rain. More passionfruit. After water, strawberry jam on pancakes. Butter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Creamy. Rice pudding. Those lemons are back, bringing with them toffee and custard bombolone. Sauternes?! Crème patisserie. Sweet pastries and croissants. Minty. After water, some more woodiness and vanilla custard sweetness. Ripe nectarines and peaches. Light minerality and acidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Menthol, eucalyptus, and lovely sweet pound cake. Powerfully warming. Toffee. Very long. Mango sorbet and vanilla. A big whack of vanilla, like those bombolone. Whipped cream and vanilla beans. Whiffs of oak rounding out the whole thing. After water, even creamier. Like a sundae! Or a banoffee tart. The creamy banana goes on forever: long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Masterclass exbourbon. Passionfruit nose is amazing, and the clarity of the bombolone pastry/vanilla/cream notes is spectacular. Big fan of Hidden Spirits. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="balmenach" /><category term="hidden-spirits" /><summary type="html">An honest little exbourbon malt from Hidden Spirits, one of my favourite bottlers. From a rather obscure distillery.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Teaninich 2006 Hidden Spirits 13 years 51.7% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-teaninich-2006-hidden-spirits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaninich 2006 Hidden Spirits 13 years 51.7% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/teaninich-2006-hidden-spirits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-teaninich-2006-hidden-spirits.html">&lt;p&gt;Another Hidden Spirit, this time from Teaninich. Not quite as obscure as Balmenach, but not exactly hyped… hope you like salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Huge malt. big banana. Candlewax? Watermelon, rockmelon. Stone fruits. A bit of a fruit platter here. Cucumber and a bit of salt. A little meaty after some time. Very full. With a bit of water, reveals floral notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Woah. Light Cucumber and caramel. Watermelon and salt. Fresh melons and lemonade icy-poles. Caramel and toffee, brown sugar. Malt, corn flakes. Cucumber again! What’s going on? With water, sweeter, sugar cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Perfumed. Dried fruits. Chai lattes and apples. Fresh salad (cucumber…). Very long, very pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Haha, so weird. Cucumber and salad? Melons and meat? Typical fresh fruits and caramel? Wild stuff. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="teaninich" /><category term="hidden-spirits" /><summary type="html">Another Hidden Spirit, this time from Teaninich. Not quite as obscure as Balmenach, but not exactly hyped… hope you like salad.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Springbank “Cask Strength” 12 years 55.3% (2020)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-springbank-12-cs.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Springbank “Cask Strength” 12 years 55.3% (2020)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/springbank-12-cs</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-springbank-12-cs.html">&lt;p&gt;The 2020 release of Springbank’s cask strength 12 year old. From what I gather, it’s 35 per cent sherry and 65 per cent exbourbon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Deep gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Rubber and soot, yeasty funk. Springbank funk. Apricots. Figs and dates. Berry jams. Vanilla bean sugar. Filo pastry. Cream and tropical fruits: bananas, mangoes. Fennel and mint. Blueberry yoghurt. Wood and earth. With water, woodier and earthier, and a hint of chocolate, and a little roasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Thick. Very sweet! Golden syrup over pancakes, lemon and sugar. Citrus peels. Oily. Very dirty, earthy – light peat. Leathery. A little smoke. Rice pudding, fresh orchard fruits, fruit jams, and creamy malt. Rubber and wood. Dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Hot – intense. Raspberry jam and rubbery funk. Soot and ash. Coffee and milk. Cream. Pears. A little tannic. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Monstrous. A striking balance between rubbery funk, earthy peat, and fruity notes. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="springbank" /><summary type="html">The 2020 release of Springbank’s cask strength 12 year old. From what I gather, it’s 35 per cent sherry and 65 per cent exbourbon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glenrothes 2006 Wilson and Morgan 48% (first fill sherry butts)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-glenrothes-2006-wilson-morgan.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glenrothes 2006 Wilson and Morgan 48% (first fill sherry butts)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glenrothes-2006-wilson-morgan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-glenrothes-2006-wilson-morgan.html">&lt;p&gt;A vatting of three casks. First fill sherry butts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Rose gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Sherry! Dried fruits and brown sugar. A little cheesy? Definitely. Cheddar and black pepper. Oak and baking spices. Armagnac.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Full and creamy. Dried fruits, apricot delight. Peaches and nectarines. Brightness: orange juice. Jaffa cakes. Sweet malt. Oak tannins. Thick caramel and brown sugar: very Glenrothes. Lollipops and vanilla. Tannic. Hazelnuts and walnuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Warming and spicy. Fruit mince tarts and tiramisu. Rummy: molasses. Oak. Long. A little tannic and stemmy. Stewed pears. Nutty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Straightforward, honest, sherry forward dram. Loving the Glenrothes malt — caramel works so well. 83/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glenrothes" /><category term="wilson-morgan" /><summary type="html">A vatting of three casks. First fill sherry butts.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blair Athol 2003 Douglas of Drumlanrig 12 years 46% (refill hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-blair-athol-2003-dod.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blair Athol 2003 Douglas of Drumlanrig 12 years 46% (refill hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/blair-athol-2003-dod</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-blair-athol-2003-dod.html">&lt;p&gt;Presumably an exbourbon refill hoggy. One of Diageo’s blend focused distilleries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Fresh fruits and bananas, perfume and menthol. Boiled sweets and sweetened cream. Heady, alcoholic, surprising for a 46 per cent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Caramel. A slight astringency. Malt, bright acidic oranges. Oily zest. Pretty light, a little grassy and slightly floral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Nutty, coconut. A little oak and some bitter herbs. Moderate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Pretty light on. Overall, too simple and dull. Perfumed nose and the zesty notes carry most of the interest. 75/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="blair-athol" /><category term="douglas-of-drumlanrig" /><summary type="html">Presumably an exbourbon refill hoggy. One of Diageo’s blend focused distilleries.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ben Nevis 2015 Adelphi 5 years 61.3% (first fill sherry)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-ben-nevis-2015-adelphi.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ben Nevis 2015 Adelphi 5 years 61.3% (first fill sherry)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ben-nevis-2015-adelphi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-ben-nevis-2015-adelphi.html">&lt;p&gt;Adelphi! I got the email for this outturn at ten in the morning, I believe. Three minutes later, this was sold out (alongside most of the other bottles in this outturn). Oh well, c’est la vie. The people love the colour. Judging by the number of bottles (622), probably a sherry butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Deep ruby. I guess we know what to expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Sherry. Dirty and oily, mint and menthol. Dried fruits and walnuts. Fresh oak. Herbaceous. Heady and alcoholic, but not unpleasant. Perfume. Toffee apples. Pears. Cough syrup. Minty. Lilly pilly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Oily Bennie smack. Dried fruits, figs and raisins. A little ashy, before moving into dried apricots and more figs. Coco pops, raisin bran, and honey granola. Candied macadamias. Boiled sweets and vanilla. Cola.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Mulled wine. Cinnamon and chilli. Raisins, sultanas, PX. Thick and heavy. Molasses, very long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Real classic Adelphi sherry bomb. Young Bennie is great stuff. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ben-nevis" /><category term="adelphi" /><summary type="html">Adelphi! I got the email for this outturn at ten in the morning, I believe. Three minutes later, this was sold out (alongside most of the other bottles in this outturn). Oh well, c’est la vie. The people love the colour. Judging by the number of bottles (622), probably a sherry butt.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Secret Highland 2010 Claxton’s Exploration 10 years 50% (tawny port butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-secret-highland-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Secret Highland 2010 Claxton’s Exploration 10 years 50% (tawny port butt)" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/secret-highland-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-secret-highland-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Another Claxton’s Exploration bottling. This time a secret highland. Coordinates are 58.02N, 3.87W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Rose gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Waxy malt – candlewax. Brown sugar and caramelised apples. Apple pie! Cinnamon and a hint of cloves. Vanilla. Dried fruits and red wine – port-like. Fresh apple juice. Very enticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Sharp, bright, a little acidity. Sweet and thick too, almost like a nice balsamic vinegar. Huge waxy malt! Stewed and dried fruits, fruit mince tart. Very spicy. Some oak and woodiness. Mulled wine and cinnamon sticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Vanilla bean ice cream and cinnamon. Apples. So, apple pie and ice cream. Hot molasses. Malty. Nutella. Moderately long, but the heat and spices do linger. Hot apple juice (yes…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Cracking stuff. Very harmonious: a sense of apple pie served alongside vanilla ice cream persists throughout the whole experience. You’ll be pleased to know that the malt is indeed there and there’s a few other notes to keep us on our toes. Cheerful – I suspect if the distillery was properly named and bumped to cask strength I’d be paying double the price. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="undisclosed" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">Another Claxton’s Exploration bottling. This time a secret highland. Coordinates are 58.02N, 3.87W.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Islay 2012 Claxton’s Exploration 8 years 50% (refill sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-islay-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Islay 2012 Claxton’s Exploration 8 years 50% (refill sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/islay-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-islay-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;The final Claxton’s Exploration I’ll be looking at for now. We’ve got another blended malt – presumably teaspooned. Coordinates are 55.63N, 6.15W. This one leads to a quite legendary south coast Islay distillery. Thoughts on the bottling series itself also after the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Peat. Intensely herbal and medicinal. Fire and sand. Seaweed and salt. Heavy, sticky, orange almond cake. Minerally and coastal malt, salty. A little woody, but fresh. Plum sauce and wine gummies (hello cask?). Some pepper and menthol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Thick, oily and medicinal – almost bitter (this is a pleasant thing). Moss, smoke: peat. South coast in character. Scotch fingers and grain – malt. Black tea. Some sweetness, and a fruity, berry note. Like a handful of blueberries and raspberries. Cream. Interesting contrasts here. Back to grassy and herbal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Oil and smoke. Cough syrup, but the sweetness isn’t artificial. Varnish. Bready. A touch of olive oil. Moderate, but the peat does power on. And isn’t that what we signed up for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Classic south coast Islay style. Through the peat it does strike me as a lighter malt. I’m very much enjoying the fresh woodsy notes: herbs, grass. It’s a bit like a forest meeting the coast. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, Claxton’s Exploration series is probably my favourite entry level IB lineup. I’m impressed by both the quality and value of these bottlings. I strongly recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="islay" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">The final Claxton’s Exploration I’ll be looking at for now. We’ve got another blended malt – presumably teaspooned. Coordinates are 55.63N, 6.15W. This one leads to a quite legendary south coast Islay distillery. Thoughts on the bottling series itself also after the fold.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ardmore 2009 Claxton’s Exploration 11 years 50% (refill PX hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-ardmore-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ardmore 2009 Claxton’s Exploration 11 years 50% (refill PX hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ardmore-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-ardmore-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing on our Claxton’s Exploration. We’ve got an Ardmore – single malt, very much disclosed distillery. There’s no mystery this time, but the coordinates are 57.35N, 2.74W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Cedarwood and lacquer. Herbal bouquet garni: rosemary, mint, coriander. Peppercorns. Milk chocolate and chilli. Floral malt with a stir of caramel. Light woody peat and smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Looking like we’re starting off with some syrupy raisins. Very sweet. Wait. Chocolate bomb! Huge amounts of milk chocolate combined with a whack of woody peat – the perfect amount. Cedar. Moving into all smoke and chocolatey malt. It’s like someone took a hot chocolate and set it on fire. Malty, caramel body, milky texture. A little bit spicy and that herbal note from the nose flows through here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Impressively long, unexpected. Hot chocolate. smoke. Hazelnut pralines. Sugared. Leather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Chocolate and woody peat smoke. A milk chocolate hazelnut praline in a bottle. Impressive, but mostly huge amounts of fun. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ardmore" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">Continuing on our Claxton’s Exploration. We’ve got an Ardmore – single malt, very much disclosed distillery. There’s no mystery this time, but the coordinates are 57.35N, 2.74W.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Campbeltown Blend 2015 Claxton’s Exploration 5 years 50% (PX hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-30-campbeltown-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Campbeltown Blend 2015 Claxton’s Exploration 5 years 50% (PX hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/campbeltown-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-30-campbeltown-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Part of the inaugural outturn of Claxton’s Exploration series comes a blended malt from Campbeltown. As I understand it, this is a teaspooned malt. It spent only five years in a PX hogshead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A teaspooned malt is one where a teaspoon (quite literally) of malt from another distillery is added to what would otherwise be a single malt. Legally you can no longer sell it as a single malt. This may have tax advantages or is perhaps demanded by the distillery themselves. If you’re curious as to what the vast majority of this malt is, Claxton’s have helpfully provided longitude and latitude coordinates on the label: 55.43 N, 5.60 W. Happy mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly this bottle came with a coin underneath the cork seal. You can redeem five of these coins for a well priced exclusive bottle from Claxton’s, presumably to reward people who actually &lt;em&gt;drink&lt;/em&gt; whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Oranges. Chocolate oranges. Milk chocolate digestives, honey on porridge. There’s a sort of earthiness, dirtiness to this. Fennel and menthol. This one’s pretty alcoholic, but does ease up with some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Quite a sweet malt. Classic PX dried fruits: figs, dates, raisins. Tangerines and oranges. A little chalky. Thick honey. It seems ever so slightly peated: some smoke along with earthy chocolate. A little oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Citrus peel and milk chocolate. A little spicy: cayenne and cinnamon. It’s a bit like a spiced honey tea. With the chocolate biscuits, of course. Long and especially hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; This dram needs a bit of time to open up. It’s heady and alcoholic, probably on account of its youth. But despite being a little brash, it’s a delightfully sweet and earthy malt with an orange twist. 82/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="campbeltown" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">Part of the inaugural outturn of Claxton’s Exploration series comes a blended malt from Campbeltown. As I understand it, this is a teaspooned malt. It spent only five years in a PX hogshead.</summary></entry></feed>