<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-08T00:44:58+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Port Charlotte (Bruichladdich) 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 13 years 63.5% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-07-port-charlotte-2002-rbt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Port Charlotte (Bruichladdich) 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 13 years 63.5% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-07T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/port-charlotte-2002-rbt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-07-port-charlotte-2002-rbt.html">&lt;p&gt;Early Port Charlotte – the spirit profile was not even a year old as of this run (25 April 2002). Bottled 2016 from cask 7. From the same outturn as the 2002 Bruichladdich, but couldn’t be more different…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah! Funky, vegetal peat. Burning rubber and tire fires. Lit candles dripping with wax and pencil shavings. Dirty smoke. Juicy oranges and their oils. Sandalwood and oak. Second-hand cigar smoke. Blueberry cheesecake. Salty pretzels. There’s a briney note here too that barges in from time to time. Burnt toast with dark roast peanut butter. Roasted almonds. With water, sweeter: caramel and honey. Floral notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Upfront: monumental dirty peat. Vegetal, like the nose. Burning tires. Ash and soot. Medicinal and herbal. Eucalyptus. Then into some oily lemon acidity. Mouth-coating, thick, oily texture. Liquorice and fennel. With time, sweet fruit juice. Pancakes and butter. With water, sweet smoke and ash. Intensely peppery and a little savoury – salt and pepper tofu? Rubbery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Powerful. Dirty smoke. Incense and bonfires. Briney and meaty, mushrooms. Burnt toast. Dark chocolate, roasted hazelnuts, and a sweet, earthy body. Red berries and banana sundaes. Rubbery, herbal. Very long, intensely warming. With water, lemon and orange syrup – acidity balanced by sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Completely different in quality to the 2002 Bruichladdich. Higher ABV but the alcohol is not an impediment at all. Anyway: this stuff is on a tear. For my money, better than any Octomore. 94/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/port-charlotte-2002-rbt.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="port-charlotte" /><category term="rest-and-be-thankful" /><summary type="html">Early Port Charlotte – the spirit profile was not even a year old as of this run (25 April 2002). Bottled 2016 from cask 7. From the same outturn as the 2002 Bruichladdich, but couldn’t be more different…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bruichladdich 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 13 years 57.1% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-07-bruichladdich-2002-rbt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bruichladdich 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 13 years 57.1% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-07T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bruichladdich-2002-rbt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-07-bruichladdich-2002-rbt.html">&lt;p&gt;A couple of early neo-Laddie bottles today, both from Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful. Distilled in 2002, just after the distillery’s reopening in 2001. Bottled 2016 from cask 454.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Pencil shavings, erasers, playdough. Sweet milk and lactic funk – Yakult? Laddie funk. Biscuits and brine. Some sweet vegetal notes, shredded carrot. Overripe fruits. Butter. Chilli, white pepper. A lot of heat on this nose. With water, a little floral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Very sweet and very spicy. Malty. Alcohol covers any nuance… surprising, it’s not even close to an undrinkable ABV – not well integrated. With some water, turns into something more recognisably Bruichladdich – floral notes, honey, but the texture goes. There’s a surprising amount of astringent oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Vanilla and soft salted caramel cookies. Cinnamon cream that hangs in your throat. With water, buttery, floral flavours come to the fore. A hint of smoke?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Disappointing. This one really needs a lot of time to breathe. It’s a shame, there’s a good malt somewhere hiding under the alcohol, but you need a lot of time and water to “dial it in”. So much potential, but not my first choice. 79/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bruichladdich-2002-rbt.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="rest-and-be-thankful" /><summary type="html">A couple of early neo-Laddie bottles today, both from Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful. Distilled in 2002, just after the distillery’s reopening in 2001. Bottled 2016 from cask 454.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ben Nevis 2015 Càrn Mòr 4 years 47.5% (sherry hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-06-ben-nevis-2015-carn-mor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ben Nevis 2015 Càrn Mòr 4 years 47.5% (sherry hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-06T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-06T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ben-nevis-2015-carn-mor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-06-ben-nevis-2015-carn-mor.html">&lt;p&gt;Ben Nevis again! This time another youngster. A vatting of two casks, presumably both sherry hogsheads. Weirdly high outturn of bottles though, 900 bottles. Aren’t hogsheads around 250 litres? Even assuming zero angel’s share…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Dirty, earthy, and oily. Think deep fryer. A spread: pickled veggies, cheeses, nuts. Sherry: dried fruits, oak spices, brown sugar. A bit of an umami note, soy sauce. Big whack of cinnamon and cloves. Funky, yeasty… leather, ash. Thick oat porridge with a swirl of honey. Alcoholic, young, precocious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Milky malt, and into dried fruits: raisins, dates. Apricots. Almost a chewy, texture: fruit roll-up? Peat? Pretty hot for the ABV.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; A little boozy. Dried fruits again: raisins, dates. Black tea. Herbal and woody. A little leathery, meaty. Light smoke and ash. Puffed rice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Powerful, bold, uncomplicated. Delicious. May surprise some given the age, but there is an alcoholic edge. Nose is terrific, but the palate is a bit simple. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/carn-mor-ben-nevis-4.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ben-nevis" /><category term="carn-mor" /><summary type="html">Ben Nevis again! This time another youngster. A vatting of two casks, presumably both sherry hogsheads. Weirdly high outturn of bottles though, 900 bottles. Aren’t hogsheads around 250 litres? Even assuming zero angel’s share…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tobermory “Ledaig Unpeated” 1995 Hidden Spirits 25 years 50.2% (refill exbourbon hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-06-tobermory-1995-hidden-spirits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tobermory “Ledaig Unpeated” 1995 Hidden Spirits 25 years 50.2% (refill exbourbon hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-06T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-06T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/tobermory-1995-hidden-spirits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-06-tobermory-1995-hidden-spirits.html">&lt;p&gt;Tobermory… tick… Hidden Spirits… tick. Wait. “Ledaig Unpeated”? Shouldn’t Ledaig be “Tobermory Peated” if anything? &lt;a href=&quot;https://thelondonwhiskyclub.com/events/2021/hidden-spirits/&quot;&gt;According to Andrea&lt;/a&gt; (London Whisky Club) of Hidden Spirits, this might have been a cleaning run through the stills after a run of peated spirit. Apparently Ledaig was less peated back then, this this could easily be confused with the cleaning run. Anyway, Ledaigamory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Candlewax. Peaches and nectarines. Glossy paper magazines. Leather boots (car seats?). Brown sugar. Menthol, mint, fennel, and coriander. Peppery, brine, coastal. Boozy ice cream topped with ripe cherries. Fresh ricotta drizzled with honey. Spicy oak. Lemon balm and orange zest. Wow – as soon as you focus on to one note, the nose unfolds in a completely different way. Bit of a mindbender this one (from previous notes: spanakopita?!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Thick. Herbal and peppery. Elegant sweetness, hard to pin down, but probably peaches, kiwis, or that mild-if-anything sweetness of a scone. There’s an odd savoury note: wax? Brine? Mushrooms? Perhaps, it’s delicate, elegant, intriguing. Pour some more… yes… huge, herbaceous malt, oak and tannins. Chocolate pralines and hot spices: chilli, cayenne pepper, Sichuan peppercorn. A drop of rosewater and minerality. Citrus oils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Menthol and pepper. Salted caramel gelato. Very full, creamy. White chocolate and almonds. Weathered wood. A herbal digestif. Funky scented candles. Maybe some tropical fruits, mangoes and bananas. Should mention at this point – the intensity of this is off the charts. Similar to the 2007 Linkwood also by Hidden Spirits. Powerfully warming. Do I need to say long?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; This is a dram that inspires some poetry. Apologies for the verbal vomit. Anyway. Delicate but powerful. Elegant and complex. Intriguing, thoughtful stuff – even a little difficult. Blue and orange, yadda yadda. 91/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/tobermory-25-hisp.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="tobermory" /><category term="hidden-spirits" /><summary type="html">Tobermory… tick… Hidden Spirits… tick. Wait. “Ledaig Unpeated”? Shouldn’t Ledaig be “Tobermory Peated” if anything? According to Andrea (London Whisky Club) of Hidden Spirits, this might have been a cleaning run through the stills after a run of peated spirit. Apparently Ledaig was less peated back then, this this could easily be confused with the cleaning run. Anyway, Ledaigamory.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Montilla Oloroso NV North Star 16.9% (Scotch cask)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-06-oloroso-north-star-series-12.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Montilla Oloroso NV North Star 16.9% (Scotch cask)" /><published>2021-05-06T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-06T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/oloroso-north-star-series-12</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-06-oloroso-north-star-series-12.html">&lt;p&gt;Ever wonder what happens to the sherry used to season your cask? Usually it’s poured down a drain, but North Star bottled this one. Although it’s not technically sherry because it was made in Montilla. Anyway: from what I gather, used to season a barrel that once held whisky. So think of it as Scotch finished oloroso, not oloroso finished Scotch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Dark ruby, golden brown.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Fresh with a hint of minerality. Walnuts and almonds. Grapes. Hints of Fennel. Rum and raisin chocolate. A little boozy, estery at warmer temperatures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Quite sweet, for an oloroso! Brown sugar. Full bodied, dried fruits – sultanas and raisins. A hint of fresh acidity and grassiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Creamy, raisins and figs coated in milk chocolate. A touch of oak. long, becoming sweeter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; I reckon it’s sweeter than most olorosos, but I’ve friends that say it’s dry as the desert sands. Don’t get me wrong – it’s still a dry wine. But it is decadent. Not the best oloroso on the planet, but very interesting stuff for whisky geeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/north-star-oloroso.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="fortified-wine" /><category term="north-star" /><summary type="html">Ever wonder what happens to the sherry used to season your cask? Usually it’s poured down a drain, but North Star bottled this one. Although it’s not technically sherry because it was made in Montilla. Anyway: from what I gather, used to season a barrel that once held whisky. So think of it as Scotch finished oloroso, not oloroso finished Scotch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ledaig 2010 Chorlton 10 years 57% (bourbon barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-ledaig-2010-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ledaig 2010 Chorlton 10 years 57% (bourbon barrel)" /><published>2021-05-05T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ledaig-2010-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-ledaig-2010-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Final dram of the Chorlton night. Ledaig, of Tobermory fame. Or should that be Tobermory, of Ledaig fame? Anyway, absolute heavyweight. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final bit of Chorlton trivia: David bottles all of his stuff to his own tastes. From the source: highland style or peated, no odd finishes or wine casks. Very orthodox stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Fish oil. Meaty. Dirty, rubbery, oily, phenolic peat and smoke. Spices, but not the typical: chilli, cayenne, black pepper, fennel. Dehydrated apples and apricots (cocktail garnishes!). Cherries and lychees, berry coulis. Acute minerality. Vanilla caramel and roasted hazelnuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Brown sugar sweetness on the attack. Then into dirty peat. Rubber, tire fires. Vegetation. Ash and soot. But then into cream, full woodiness. Floral. Grassy. Balances well with the umami on the nose. Dirt again. Smoked pears. Malt. A little nutty, peanuts? The peat’s back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Excuse the poetry: you’re on the beach, and you’ve lit a little peat fire in your heart. Deeply warming. Coastal, salty. Belching smoke and dirty peat. Chocolate and peanuts: Whittaker’s Peanut Slab. A little citric at the very end. Very long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Filthy peat and belching smoke. A heavy truck passing by. A campfire on the beach. A complete pleasure to drink. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ledaig" /><category term="tobermory" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Final dram of the Chorlton night. Ledaig, of Tobermory fame. Or should that be Tobermory, of Ledaig fame? Anyway, absolute heavyweight. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lochindaal (Bruichladdich) 2007 Chorlton 12 years 61.9% (bourbon barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-lochindaal-2007-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lochindaal (Bruichladdich) 2007 Chorlton 12 years 61.9% (bourbon barrel)" /><published>2021-05-05T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/lochindaal-2007-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-lochindaal-2007-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Lochindaal was a peated spirit made by Bruichladdich shortly after they opened. More heavily peated than Port Charlotte. David says that it’s more like a peated Laddie spirit – it’s got that clarity we’d associate with it. I agree with him. Unfortunately, Bruichladdich is no longer making Lochindaal. Perhaps not a lost distillery, but a lost malt! Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Chorlton trivia: David runs the thing by himself, and got started by running his own tastings in Chorlton, Manchester. Then he bottled some cask ends, and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Vanilla custard. Medicinal – elevated cough syrup. Umami: meaty and mushroomy. Seaweed and seawater near the beach. Very clean, austere spirit, very much akin to regular Bruichladdich. Fennel and aniseed. Honeyed and floral. A small yeasty, lactic, funky note. Salty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Deeply medicinal. Definitely elevated cough syrup. Syrupy in texture too, thick. Earthy, woody peat. Raspberry jellies, strawberries and cream. Jam and scones. Honey and fennel, carrying with it some ginger. A little acidity, lime juice. Herbal malt. Some citrus peel – don’t forget the pith. Oily. Smoke – and quite a lot of it at the tail end, leading into the finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Mouth-filling smoke. It’s got volume. Very long. Warming. Ashy and earthy. Creamy. Tropical fruits: mangoes and bananas. Ice cream sundae. Very clear. Full, powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Creamy, smoky, medicinal spirit with a keen edge. Swims well. The bones are Bruichladdich. I simply cannot say anything bad about this malt. 92/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="lochindaal" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Lochindaal was a peated spirit made by Bruichladdich shortly after they opened. More heavily peated than Port Charlotte. David says that it’s more like a peated Laddie spirit – it’s got that clarity we’d associate with it. I agree with him. Unfortunately, Bruichladdich is no longer making Lochindaal. Perhaps not a lost distillery, but a lost malt! Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Orkney 2005 Chorlton 15 years 57.1% (refill bourbon hogshead, apparently)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-orkney-2005-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orkney 2005 Chorlton 15 years 57.1% (refill bourbon hogshead, apparently)" /><published>2021-05-05T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/orkney-2005-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-orkney-2005-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of secret Orkney casks lately. No surprises: Highland Park! Are they having a sale or something? And what’s with this cask? Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Chorlton trivia: apparently a lot of his casks are now held at Dalswinton Bond, a dunnage warehouse. Smells good, I imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Dark gold, ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Wow. Exbourbon? No way. Sautéed mushrooms and soy sauce. Really quite thick, brothy, fatty. Stinky cheese. Balsamic vinegar – woody sweetness and acidity together. Salt and vinegar chips. Tart apples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Malty. A big whack of red fruits, berries. Syrupy dried fruits and apricot delight. It’s a bit like a sherry cask. Slightly medicinal peat. Very herbal. We’ve added a bit too much cinnamon to our milk. Thick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Medicinal peaty finish. Heavy. Off-profile for a Highland Park. Probably why it was independently bottled. Smoke. Coastal saltiness. Tamari almonds. Mushrooms and soy sauce again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Completely mental. Big, heavy, coastal malt. Clarity of the umami notes are a highlight. If you told me this was an Islay, maybe refill sherry, I’d believe you. Completely off-profile for both the (ostensible) cask and the distillery. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="orkney" /><category term="highland-park" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">A lot of secret Orkney casks lately. No surprises: Highland Park! Are they having a sale or something? And what’s with this cask? Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunnahabhain 2002 Chorlton 18 years 53.4% (sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-bunnahabhain-2002-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunnahabhain 2002 Chorlton 18 years 53.4% (sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-05T20:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T20:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bunnahabhain-2002-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-bunnahabhain-2002-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;A Christmas release for Chorlton. Apt. Sherry, but the complete opposite of a sherry bomb. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Chorlton trivia: David is buying more stock, thinking about the future. As for the past, cask prices have increased a lot over the last two years. Speculation has apparently played a role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Banana caramel milkshake. Chewy toffee. Coastal – a little salty, earthy – more sandy. Red apples, candied apples. A waft of dried fruits and spots of milk chocolate. Quite rich, which is appropriate for a Christmas release. A touch of wax. Oak spices. A splash of sherry vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Big raisin and sultana smack. but quite understated sherry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understated sherry. Entrance with classic dried fruits: raisins and sultanas. Rounded by oak spices, cinnamon, and cloves. Sweetness balanced by a touch of astringency, stemmy notes. Fruit mince tarts and panforte. Let’s riff with this Christmas theme. Oak spices, cinnamon, cloves. Thick, creamy texture. Every now and then, a pop of tart berry acidity. Interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Primarily spicy and fruity. A little tannic and tart. Not hot at all, but quite heady. Dark chocolate and coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Probably the most average bottle of the night. That said, still very high quality, and absolutely spot-on the Christmas theme. An elegant Christmas, to be sure, given the understatement of the cask. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bunnahabhain" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">A Christmas release for Chorlton. Apt. Sherry, but the complete opposite of a sherry bomb. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glenlossie 1992 Chorlton 27 years 51.2% (hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-glenlossie-1992-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glenlossie 1992 Chorlton 27 years 51.2% (hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-05T20:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T20:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glenlossie-1992-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-05-glenlossie-1992-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Early 90s Glenlossie. Reportedly (from David) amazing, underrated, the golden years. Also, I’m told, needs this kind of age. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another bit of Chorlton trivia. How does David actually buy casks? Several ways: direct cask sales, through cask brokers, or minimum purchases (parcels). Parcels might be split with other bottlers or put down for later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Strawberry liquorice. Cherries and chocolate: cherry ripe. Heapings of red berries. Acidity too: berry tartness. A drop of olive oil on the nose (semi-jokingly: late harvest). A little salty. A touch metallic – pleasing! With water: mint is back. Brown sugar. With time: waxy, potato chips, quite bready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Beeswax, honey (David: absolutely). Hyper-floral. A little earthy, but not dirty. Petrichor? Orchard fruits. Very sweet, but not sugary, elegant. Wafers and digestive biscuits. With water, more wax! Honeyed and a hint of basil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Very full sweetness. Pears and honey. Regal. Strawberry jams, quite thick. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Elegant stuff. Pure spring and summer malt. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glenlossie" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Early 90s Glenlossie. Reportedly (from David) amazing, underrated, the golden years. Also, I’m told, needs this kind of age. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry></feed>