<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-01T04:22:23+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ardmore 2009 Claxton’s Exploration 11 years 50% (refill PX hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-ardmore-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ardmore 2009 Claxton’s Exploration 11 years 50% (refill PX hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ardmore-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-ardmore-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Continuing on our Claxton’s Exploration. We’ve got an Ardmore – single malt, very much disclosed distillery. There’s no mystery this time, but the coordinates are 57.35N, 2.74W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Cedarwood and lacquer. Herbal bouquet garni: rosemary, mint, coriander. Peppercorns. Milk chocolate and chilli. Floral malt with a stir of caramel. Light woody peat and smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Looking like we’re starting off with some syrupy raisins. Very sweet. Wait. Chocolate bomb! Huge amounts of milk chocolate combined with a whack of woody peat – the perfect amount. Cedar. Moving into all smoke and chocolatey malt. It’s like someone took a hot chocolate and set it on fire. Malty, caramel body, milky texture. A little bit spicy and that herbal note from the nose flows through here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Impressively long, unexpected. Hot chocolate. smoke. Hazelnut pralines. Sugared. Leather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Chocolate and woody peat smoke. A milk chocolate hazelnut praline in a bottle. Impressive, but mostly huge amounts of fun. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ardmore" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">Continuing on our Claxton’s Exploration. We’ve got an Ardmore – single malt, very much disclosed distillery. There’s no mystery this time, but the coordinates are 57.35N, 2.74W.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Secret Highland 2010 Claxton’s Exploration 10 years 50% (tawny port butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-secret-highland-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Secret Highland 2010 Claxton’s Exploration 10 years 50% (tawny port butt)" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/secret-highland-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-secret-highland-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Another Claxton’s Exploration bottling. This time a secret highland. Coordinates are 58.02N, 3.87W.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Rose gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Waxy malt – candlewax. Brown sugar and caramelised apples. Apple pie! Cinnamon and a hint of cloves. Vanilla. Dried fruits and red wine – port-like. Fresh apple juice. Very enticing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Sharp, bright, a little acidity. Sweet and thick too, almost like a nice balsamic vinegar. Huge waxy malt! Stewed and dried fruits, fruit mince tart. Very spicy. Some oak and woodiness. Mulled wine and cinnamon sticks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Vanilla bean ice cream and cinnamon. Apples. So, apple pie and ice cream. Hot molasses. Malty. Nutella. Moderately long, but the heat and spices do linger. Hot apple juice (yes…).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Cracking stuff. Very harmonious: a sense of apple pie served alongside vanilla ice cream persists throughout the whole experience. You’ll be pleased to know that the malt is indeed there and there’s a few other notes to keep us on our toes. Cheerful – I suspect if the distillery was properly named and bumped to cask strength I’d be paying double the price. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="undisclosed" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">Another Claxton’s Exploration bottling. This time a secret highland. Coordinates are 58.02N, 3.87W.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Islay 2012 Claxton’s Exploration 8 years 50% (refill sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-islay-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Islay 2012 Claxton’s Exploration 8 years 50% (refill sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-01T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/islay-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-01-islay-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;The final Claxton’s Exploration I’ll be looking at for now. We’ve got another blended malt – presumably teaspooned. Coordinates are 55.63N, 6.15W. This one leads to a quite legendary south coast Islay distillery. Thoughts on the bottling series itself also after the fold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Peat. Intensely herbal and medicinal. Fire and sand. Seaweed and salt. Heavy, sticky, orange almond cake. Minerally and coastal malt, salty. A little woody, but fresh. Plum sauce and wine gummies (hello cask?). Some pepper and menthol.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Thick, oily and medicinal – almost bitter (this is a pleasant thing). Moss, smoke: peat. South coast in character. Scotch fingers and grain – malt. Black tea. Some sweetness, and a fruity, berry note. Like a handful of blueberries and raspberries. Cream. Interesting contrasts here. Back to grassy and herbal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Oil and smoke. Cough syrup, but the sweetness isn’t artificial. Varnish. Bready. A touch of olive oil. Moderate, but the peat does power on. And isn’t that what we signed up for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Classic south coast Islay style. Through the peat it does strike me as a lighter malt. I’m very much enjoying the fresh woodsy notes: herbs, grass. It’s a bit like a forest meeting the coast. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, Claxton’s Exploration series is probably my favourite entry level IB lineup. I’m impressed by both the quality and value of these bottlings. I strongly recommend checking it out.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="islay" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">The final Claxton’s Exploration I’ll be looking at for now. We’ve got another blended malt – presumably teaspooned. Coordinates are 55.63N, 6.15W. This one leads to a quite legendary south coast Islay distillery. Thoughts on the bottling series itself also after the fold.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bruichladdich “The Ternary Project” 52.1%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-30-bruichladdich-ternary.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bruichladdich “The Ternary Project” 52.1%" /><published>2021-04-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bruichladdich-ternary</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-30-bruichladdich-ternary.html">&lt;p&gt;Bruichladdich’s March (April, really) ballot bottle, capping off the Valinch ballots due to the distillery’s COVID closure. The pricing on this one caused quite a stir round the whisky groups. I think price expectations were much lower for the ballot and Bruichladdich might have been better served with this as a Fèis Ìle bottle. That said, if you’re willing to buy Black Art, you should probably be willing to buy this. And wow – does it deliver.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, we’re looking at a vatting: 30 per cent pre-closure Bruichladdich, 40 per cent early Port Charlotte, and 30 per cent 2008 Octomore. Regular Laddie cask wizardry is happening here: assorted bourbon, sherry, and wine casks. Bruichladdich cannot disclose the vintages of the older components publicly, but one may consider reaching out privately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Rose gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Peat and smoke forward. Woody peat. Ash and smouldering embers. Quality Port Charlotte style – similar to a 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful. Ripe strawberries and bananas. Some spices and coffee, think a chai latte and a flat white. Woody and herbal – think medicinal. Ash. Blueberry cheesecake. Biscuity malt, and a tiny little bit lactic. There’s that Laddie funk! Granola with dried goji berries. Like breakfast! Coconut and marzipan. Dates and figs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Mouth-coating, oily. Ash and burning wood. A lot of ash, chalk. Vegetal and earthy. Minerally, salty sea air, brine. Coastal. A little leathery, meaty. A little rubbery, sulphuric. Salted caramel chocolate. Very malty, bright and citric: tangerines, oranges. Lapsang souchong. Orange peels studded with cloves. A glass of Pinot Noir with chocolate hazelnuts. Wine-forward, bright berries and rounding oak tannins. With a little water, menthol sweets and mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Bright, fresh grapes. Nutty. Loads of ash, soot. Elegant peat, woody, faint tire fires. Warming, but something more – powerful. Embers of a campfire that burns all night. Evolves into peat smoke, custard, and bananas. Lemon curd on toast. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Unmistakeable stuff. Very Bruichladdich: wine-forward, funky, elegant peat. A peated Black Art. But not an OBA: Port Charlotte is definitely taking centre stage here. It’s demanding: this is a complex dram that requires some effort and some time. 91/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><summary type="html">Bruichladdich’s March (April, really) ballot bottle, capping off the Valinch ballots due to the distillery’s COVID closure. The pricing on this one caused quite a stir round the whisky groups. I think price expectations were much lower for the ballot and Bruichladdich might have been better served with this as a Fèis Ìle bottle. That said, if you’re willing to buy Black Art, you should probably be willing to buy this. And wow – does it deliver.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Campbeltown Blend 2015 Claxton’s Exploration 5 years 50% (PX hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-30-campbeltown-claxtons-exploration.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Campbeltown Blend 2015 Claxton’s Exploration 5 years 50% (PX hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-30T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-30T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/campbeltown-claxtons-exploration</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-30-campbeltown-claxtons-exploration.html">&lt;p&gt;Part of the inaugural outturn of Claxton’s Exploration series comes a blended malt from Campbeltown. As I understand it, this is a teaspooned malt. It spent only five years in a PX hogshead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A teaspooned malt is one where a teaspoon (quite literally) of malt from another distillery is added to what would otherwise be a single malt. Legally you can no longer sell it as a single malt. This may have tax advantages or is perhaps demanded by the distillery themselves. If you’re curious as to what the vast majority of this malt is, Claxton’s have helpfully provided longitude and latitude coordinates on the label: 55.43 N, 5.60 W. Happy mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interestingly this bottle came with a coin underneath the cork seal. You can redeem five of these coins for a well priced exclusive bottle from Claxton’s, presumably to reward people who actually &lt;em&gt;drink&lt;/em&gt; whisky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Oranges. Chocolate oranges. Milk chocolate digestives, honey on porridge. There’s a sort of earthiness, dirtiness to this. Fennel and menthol. This one’s pretty alcoholic, but does ease up with some time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Quite a sweet malt. Classic PX dried fruits: figs, dates, raisins. Tangerines and oranges. A little chalky. Thick honey. It seems ever so slightly peated: some smoke along with earthy chocolate. A little oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Citrus peel and milk chocolate. A little spicy: cayenne and cinnamon. It’s a bit like a spiced honey tea. With the chocolate biscuits, of course. Long and especially hot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; This dram needs a bit of time to open up. It’s heady and alcoholic, probably on account of its youth. But despite being a little brash, it’s a delightfully sweet and earthy malt with an orange twist. 82/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="campbeltown" /><category term="claxtons-exploration" /><summary type="html">Part of the inaugural outturn of Claxton’s Exploration series comes a blended malt from Campbeltown. As I understand it, this is a teaspooned malt. It spent only five years in a PX hogshead.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Springbank (Longrow) 1994 North Star 25 years 48.5% (refill exbourbon hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-springbank-longrow-north-star.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Springbank (Longrow) 1994 North Star 25 years 48.5% (refill exbourbon hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/springbank-longrow-north-star</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-springbank-longrow-north-star.html">&lt;p&gt;Part of North Star’s recent Springbank lineup. Labelled as Springbank, peated and double distilled. Both Springbank and North Star are highly respected and popular, so as expected, it flew off the shelves…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; An immediate attack of banana, rockmelon, pawpaw, and star anise. Springbank funk: rubbery and herbal. Cookies and cream ice cream and stem ginger. Vegetal peat and a touch of smoke: smoked mushrooms. Vanilla and white chocolate. Pineapple. Incredible. Intoxicatingly fruity, herbal, and rubbery, as if it’s got a texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy. Hot chilies. So malty, with that rubbery Springbank character. Anise and caraway, lapsang souchong and watermelon.  Cherries and ripe bananas. Yoghurt and rosewater. Textured milk and floral notes. Oily. Complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Regal peat, smoke and tires. Tropical fruits and black tea again. Dark chocolate. Moderately long but very warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Technically flawless stuff. Ridiculous amounts of ripe tropical fruits. Regal peatsmoke and the classic rubbery Springbank character. One of the most complex, balanced drams out there. 94/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="springbank" /><category term="north-star" /><summary type="html">Part of North Star’s recent Springbank lineup. Labelled as Springbank, peated and double distilled. Both Springbank and North Star are highly respected and popular, so as expected, it flew off the shelves…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Secret Highland 2010 Hand-in-Hand 10 years 52.4% (refill exbourbon hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-secret-highland-hand-in-hand-3rd-release.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Secret Highland 2010 Hand-in-Hand 10 years 52.4% (refill exbourbon hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/secret-highland-hand-in-hand-3rd-release</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-secret-highland-hand-in-hand-3rd-release.html">&lt;p&gt;Bottled by a triumvirate of Australian whisky institutions: Whisky and Alement, the Oak Barrel, and Casa de Vinos. Titled “Bees &amp;amp; Fruit Trees” with a cheeky wax-on-wax-off reference label by Blake Wilson. Thoughts jump (like a cat) to mind of a distillery associated with wax…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; White wine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Honey! Wax and perfume, walnuts, whipped cream and fresh orchard fruits. Stone fruits. Honeycomb and beeswax (really…). Buttery and a little woody. Burnt macadamias. Marzipan. Molasses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Orchard fruits, covered in honey. Some spices: cinnamon, cloves, cayenne pepper. Oily, waxy body. Malty. Fruity and creamy, and the nuts return: walnut pie. Some vanilla, oak, coconut, and dried fruits at the end. With water, more brightness – fresh apple juice and pepper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy, waxy, and perfumed. Fruity, a little floral. Loads of malt, custard, dates. Spectacular finish, quite long too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Stellar stuff. Full bodied, very fruity, nutty, and yes, waxy – although that could be my mind playing tricks on me. Brash and in-your-face with these primary flavours. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="undisclosed" /><category term="hand-in-hand" /><summary type="html">Bottled by a triumvirate of Australian whisky institutions: Whisky and Alement, the Oak Barrel, and Casa de Vinos. Titled “Bees &amp;amp; Fruit Trees” with a cheeky wax-on-wax-off reference label by Blake Wilson. Thoughts jump (like a cat) to mind of a distillery associated with wax…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Arran 2013 Fisherman’s Retreat 7 years 50% (Yalumba Viognier cask)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-arran-viognier-tfr.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Arran 2013 Fisherman’s Retreat 7 years 50% (Yalumba Viognier cask)" /><published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/arran-viognier-tfr</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-arran-viognier-tfr.html">&lt;p&gt;A cask you don’t see every day. Distilled by Arran and put into a Viognier cask from Yalumba (South Australia). Bottled by the Fisherman’s Retreat as part of their limited edition series. I do have the cask strength bottling, but today I’m looking at the 50%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Bright gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Acidic: Oranges, lemons, limes. Fresh grapes. Unsurprisingly, white wine. Fruit stems. Sticky fruit buns. Maple syrup. Chai latte. A little volatile for the ABV. Lavender tea. Heady and addictive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Like the nose – bright, mouth-watering acidity. Lovely. Loaded to brim with citrus and white wine. Some heavy sweetness: a white wine vinegar reduction? Creamy texture, and a malty body reminding you that yes, this is indeed a whisky, not an incredible wine. Leads into milk chocolate. Hints of rosemary and fennel. A little roasted hazelnut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Fresh. Candied citrus peels. Spices: cloves, fennel, cumin. Not at all hot, extremely long. Winey. A small but noticeable and pleasant amount of tannins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Cracking. Even though it’s Viognier, this is sort of what I might expect (and honestly, hope) from a masterclass Sauternes cask. Winey, citrusy, creamy malt that packs a punch on account of its youth. I don’t think that’s a fault at all. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="arran" /><category term="fishermans-retreat" /><summary type="html">A cask you don’t see every day. Distilled by Arran and put into a Viognier cask from Yalumba (South Australia). Bottled by the Fisherman’s Retreat as part of their limited edition series. I do have the cask strength bottling, but today I’m looking at the 50%.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linkwood 2007 Hidden Spirits 13 years 54.1% (refill exbourbon hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2007-hidden-spirits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linkwood 2007 Hidden Spirits 13 years 54.1% (refill exbourbon hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/linkwood-2007-hidden-spirits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2007-hidden-spirits.html">&lt;p&gt;Linkwood is a distillery you don’t see often bottled by Diageo themselves. Fortunately it is a relatively common malt among independent bottlers. Here we’ve got one from Hidden Spirits, a small Italian independent bottler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Rockmelon, flowers, caramel and basil. White wine: Viognier? Lemon candy. Fresh and grassy. A little stemmy – think an apple plus some greenery. Springtime. Whiffs of coconut and fresh marmalade on toast. Museli. As it sits the coconut gets stronger: lamingtons. Incredibly perfumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Powerful stuff! Floral explosion. So bright and a little spicy – chilli heat. Lemons, bergamot, and more flowers. Into the malt. Thick: cookies and cake batter. Complements the acidity well. A little minerality, chalk. Interesting! Lightly honeyed and incredibly floral, woodsy – not oak, but a bit like a small overgrown garden. Orange peels. Something strongly alternative-medicinal: eucalyptus, tea tree oil. A little water emphasises these characters, plus a little pepper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Deeply warming and spicy. Floral. Hot honey and mulled wine: cinnamon, cloves. Ginger. Pawpaw and eucalyptus. Green apples and tropical fruits. Banana. Extremely long. Perhaps the warmest finish in recent memory. Gum leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; This malt is insane. Unrepentantly distillate forward. Complex. Floral, citrusy, spice bomb. 91/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="linkwood" /><category term="hidden-spirits" /><summary type="html">Linkwood is a distillery you don’t see often bottled by Diageo themselves. Fortunately it is a relatively common malt among independent bottlers. Here we’ve got one from Hidden Spirits, a small Italian independent bottler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linkwood 2009 Single Malts of Scotland (Elixir) 10 years 48% (seven cask vatting)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2009-smos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linkwood 2009 Single Malts of Scotland (Elixir) 10 years 48% (seven cask vatting)" /><published>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/linkwood-2009-smos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2009-smos.html">&lt;p&gt;Another Linkwood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw. Likely refill hogsheads for most of the vatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Floral and perfumed: reminds me a bit of an Armagnac. Honey, mead. Acidity: lemons and limes, white wine. Lemon peel. Lychee and unripe berries. Bready malt. A little herbal and woody. Green apples stewing away for a pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Acidic and floral. The Octomore of flowers. Buttery and thick, like a croissant. Tangerines, lemons, and limes, particularly the peels. Oily. Savoury and spicy malt to complement the flowers. It’s like some citrus jam on croissants absolutely covered in flowers. Drinks a little hotter than 48%. More malt, cream. Tea-like: earl grey with sugar. Eucalyptus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Chilli peppers, more flowers and croissants. Textured milk and white chocolate. Intensely long and warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; A lovely floral dram. I’m really digging the croissants mixed with fresh acidity. Delicious everyday whisky. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="linkwood" /><category term="elixir" /><summary type="html">Another Linkwood.</summary></entry></feed>