<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-09T22:50:13+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Clynelish 1995 Signatory Vintage 20 years 43%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-clynelish-1995-sv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clynelish 1995 Signatory Vintage 20 years 43%" /><published>2021-05-09T21:50:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:50:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/clynelish-1995-sv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-clynelish-1995-sv.html">&lt;p&gt;Nice bottle. Part of Signatory’s “Decanter Collection”. A lot of what I assume to be floccing in the bottle, so unlikely to be chill filtered, even at 43 per cent ABV. Bottled in 2016, before Clynelish got weird about people using their name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Wax and apples. Classic Clynelish. Pain aux raisins. Caramel. A whack of perfume — well integrated. Melon skins. Ice cream sundaes: fatty. A bit fresh: tomato and cucumber. Some almonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Milky texture. Orchard fruits and boiled lollies. Candlewax. Orange peel. Cinnamon and other assorted baking spices. Malty! Texture is unfortunately thinning… now we’ve got some red berries, some stemminess. A little bit of oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy — oak spices. Cinnamon and cloves. Orchard fruits and wax. A hint of tropical fruits — creamy bananas. Coconut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Disappointing. Proof does it no favours. Classic flavours but dialed down. 82/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/clynelish-1995-sv.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="clynelish" /><category term="signatory-vintage" /><summary type="html">Nice bottle. Part of Signatory’s “Decanter Collection”. A lot of what I assume to be floccing in the bottle, so unlikely to be chill filtered, even at 43 per cent ABV. Bottled in 2016, before Clynelish got weird about people using their name.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glen Flagler “Rare All-Malt Scotch” 5 years 40%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-glen-flagler-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glen Flagler “Rare All-Malt Scotch” 5 years 40%" /><published>2021-05-09T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glen-flagler-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-glen-flagler-5.html">&lt;p&gt;Silent distillery. Bottling apparently for the Italian market. Parafilmed and everything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw. Unlikely any colouring here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Waxy and vegetal. Rather perfumed. Orchard fruits: pears, apples, ripe. Carrots and celery. Candied apples, boiled sweets. Lemon and limes. Citrus peels and their oils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; A little watery – probably the ABV. Great herbal notes. Lemon balm. Apples, pears, orchard fruits. Caramel malt. A touch of wax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Moderate, quite mild. Mostly malt. Apple and pear danishes. Chai latte, predominantly cinnamon. Swirls of caramel. Milk chocolate and hazelnuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Classic profile, one imagines. Wish it was bottled at a higher proof, texture lets it down. 82/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/glen-flagler-5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glen-flagler" /><summary type="html">Silent distillery. Bottling apparently for the Italian market. Parafilmed and everything!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bowmore 2001 Hunter Laing 13 years 58.5% (refill hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-bowmore-2001-hunter-laing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bowmore 2001 Hunter Laing 13 years 58.5% (refill hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-09T21:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:30:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bowmore-2001-hunter-laing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-bowmore-2001-hunter-laing.html">&lt;p&gt;OB Bowmore gets a bit of a bad rep. Luckily this is not OB. Bottled for Shinanoya in Japan under Hunter Laing’s “Old Malt Cask” label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Vegetal and fruity. Celery, carrot, mangoes. Fresh and grassy (no understatement here). Orchard fruits, tart, apples and pears. Waxy fruit. Scented, lightly perfumed candles. Here we go: some elegant peat. Mossy, heady stuff. Rosewater. With some water, forested: wet oak, mushrooms, flowers, flowing creeks. A bit new age: incense, and a drop of oil. Turkish delight and rosewater – clarity of these is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Grassy, mossy peat. Ash and soot. Honey, caramel malt. Very malt forward, lovely. Liquorice and other assorted sweets. Bright, lemon-lime acidity. A hint of bark, not unlike bitters. With water: lemon syrup and orange peel. Don’t forget the pith!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; A touch of smoke, but mainly vegetal peat. Light honey. Oats and rosewater. Very floral, malty. Scented candles. Hot and warming, quite long. Scented smoke throughout. With water, smokier and earthier. Turkish delight. Watermelon, rockmelon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Elegance is the first word that comes to mind. Woody, scented, malt-driven. The antithesis to your dime-a-dozen smoke bomb
Islay. I also love rosewater. 89/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bowmore-2001-hl.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bowmore" /><category term="hunter-laing" /><summary type="html">OB Bowmore gets a bit of a bad rep. Luckily this is not OB. Bottled for Shinanoya in Japan under Hunter Laing’s “Old Malt Cask” label.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aultmore 2010 Infrequent Fliers 10 years 58.5% (refill barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-aultmore-2010-awwc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aultmore 2010 Infrequent Fliers 10 years 58.5% (refill barrel)" /><published>2021-05-09T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/aultmore-2010-awwc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-aultmore-2010-awwc.html">&lt;p&gt;One of Alistair Walker’s Infrequent Fliers – a relatively recent independent bottler. Now, picture a sunny day, a swim-in bar…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Tropical explosion. Pineapples and bananas. Pina colada. Pineapple chocolates. Honey and perfume. A little grassy, fresh. Some mint. Candied apples and vanilla. Malt. With water, some nectarines and white grapes shine through. Back to bananas! But those candy bananas?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Pina colada again. Creamy and spicy — chilli, cayenne. Pineapples, bananas, mangoes. Very tropical. Brown sugar syrup. With water, more malt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Mint. Dessicated coconut and pineapple juice. White chocolate and almonds. Bananas (again…). Caramel and a hint of cherries. Long. Warming. A touch of oak. With water, minty notes come to the fore, with some cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; If we’ve smoke bombs, peat bombs, sherry bombs, then this is a tropical bomb. Lovely malt. Impressive clarity. Pina colada, anyone? 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/aultmore-2010-awwc.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="aultmore" /><category term="awwc" /><summary type="html">One of Alistair Walker’s Infrequent Fliers – a relatively recent independent bottler. Now, picture a sunny day, a swim-in bar…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Highland Park 2006 Gordon &amp;amp; Macphail 14 years 58.5% (refill sherry puncheon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-highland-park-2006-gm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Highland Park 2006 Gordon &amp;amp; Macphail 14 years 58.5% (refill sherry puncheon)" /><published>2021-05-09T21:10:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:10:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/highland-park-2006-gm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-highland-park-2006-gm.html">&lt;p&gt;A recent non-secret Orkney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Malt. Dried fruits and a whack of salinity. Mint and heavily iced cookies. Manuka honey and a bit of wood. Tropical fruits: bananas, mangoes. A touch of wax. Double coat Tim Tams and Milk chocolate digestives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Very malty, sweet caramel. Some woody, smoky peat. Milk chocolate. Black pepper. Very creamy, thick mouthfeel. Alcohol is well integrated. A few herbal, menthol notes in the background tying it all together. Some smoked desserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Chocolate milk and smoke. Dried berries and coffee. Very malty! Quite long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Solid, orthodox, traditional HP. Sweet chocolate, coastal characteristics rounded by earthy peat. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/highland-park-2006-gm.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="highland-park" /><category term="gordon-macphail" /><summary type="html">A recent non-secret Orkney.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Baron Gaston Legrand 1987 Armagnac-Ténarèze 46%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-legrand-1987-armagnac.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Baron Gaston Legrand 1987 Armagnac-Ténarèze 46%" /><published>2021-05-09T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/legrand-1987-armagnac</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-legrand-1987-armagnac.html">&lt;p&gt;Bottled 24 February 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Deep amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Brown sugar. An explosion of both fresh and dried grapes. Fresh and leafy. Cinnamon buns. Candied orange and lemon peels: panettone! Beautifully perfumed. Oaky kick. A bit of chalk and minerality. Prunes and dates. Brioche. A splash of acidity: orange juice. Pears. So aromatic. A drop of soy sauce.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Silky mouthfeel. Grape acidity and an elegant sweetness: fruit jams and marmalade. Very rich, moreish. Stewed fruits. Strawberry tarts and apple danishes. A little bit of greenness to it, a stemmy astringency: pleasant! Oaky notes: cinnamon and vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Perfumed, and a little bit of oak. Brown sugar and hot cross buns. Baking spices. Creamy gelato. Full and warning. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Grand old Armagnac from my favourite region. Love the minerality on the nose. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/legrand-1987-armagnac.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="armagnac" /><category term="legrand" /><summary type="html">Bottled 24 February 2015.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ardbeg “An Oa” 46.6% (virgin oak, PX, first fill bourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-08-ardbeg-an-oa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ardbeg “An Oa” 46.6% (virgin oak, PX, first fill bourbon)" /><published>2021-05-08T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-08T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ardbeg-an-oa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-08-ardbeg-an-oa.html">&lt;p&gt;NAS Ardbeg. Core range. Hype casks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Vegetal, medicinal peat and tropical fruits. Rubber and bananas. Fresh grapes, bubblegum. Black liquorice and assorted lollies. A nice touch of acidity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Vegetal peat and fruity caramel. Malt, and a watery mouthfeel, though it does thicken a touch. Becoming sweeter – herbal sweetness. Fennel and aniseed. Light notes of dried fruits. There’s a savoury, perhaps mushroomy edge to the palate and a touch of tangerines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Smoke, rosemary oil, and liquorice. Vegetal peat, shredded carrots. Ash and orange juice – sweetness and acidity. Smoked veggies. Long and smoky. Very warming. Some astringency and a touch of salt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Perfectly pleasant peated malt. The sweetness of the nose and relative dryness of the finish is an interesting contrast. 84/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ardbeg" /><summary type="html">NAS Ardbeg. Core range. Hype casks.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Octomore “X4+10” (Bruichladdich) 10 years 70% (bourbon, sweet wine, sherry)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-08-octomore-x4-10.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Octomore “X4+10” (Bruichladdich) 10 years 70% (bourbon, sweet wine, sherry)" /><published>2021-05-08T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-08T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/octomore-x4-10</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-08-octomore-x4-10.html">&lt;p&gt;The second Octomore concept release: Octomore X4+10 Concept 0.2. Let me draw attention to the ABV: 70 per cent. Let me draw attention to why that is: quadruple distilled. Let me draw attention to the age statement: 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Banana, caramel, cream. Banana caramel sundae? There’s some oak here. More cream and tropical fruits. Brown sugar cookies. Dark roast peanut butter. It’s actually quite impressive that these notes exist at this ABV – very well integrated. With a bit of water, roasted hazelnuts and almonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Banana and caramel again. A little funky, reminiscent of a high-ester rum. Very sweet, sugary. With water, some herbal and spicy notes: lavender and cloves. Some tart berries and a welcome dose of acidity. Is that smoke? Heavy, creamy, chocolate cake and smoke? Well, there’s some boiled sweets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Esters and whipped cream. A hint of dried fruits. Soft-serve ice cream and a chocolate flake. Banana bread. Malty, rounded. Very long. With water, it becomes supremely malty. Waffles. Boiled sweets and more cream. Lovely! Banoffee tart. As a final goodbye, some menthol and mint.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; This malt is bananas. Bananas ABV and bananas in the tasting notes. Not sure I’m behind quadruple distillation. The peat has disappeared completely and the dram is simpler than expected. That said, the clarity is impressive and it is well executed. For an Octomore, too extreme, unbalanced. For a whisky, solid stuff. Also on the border of being an explosion hazard. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/octomore-x4-10.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="octomore" /><summary type="html">The second Octomore concept release: Octomore X4+10 Concept 0.2. Let me draw attention to the ABV: 70 per cent. Let me draw attention to why that is: quadruple distilled. Let me draw attention to the age statement: 10 years.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Octomore “OBA” (Bruichladdich) 59.7% (undisclosed)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-08-octomore-oba.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Octomore “OBA” (Bruichladdich) 59.7% (undisclosed)" /><published>2021-05-08T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-08T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/octomore-oba</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-08-octomore-oba.html">&lt;p&gt;First of the Octomore Concept releases: Octomore OBA Concept 0.1. Bruichladdich will not disclose anything about this except the ABV. Basically: Octomore Black Art.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Dark gold, ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Waves and waves of perfumed smoke. A blast of acidity and flavour from oranges and lemons. Fruit mince tarts – especially boozy. Jam, scones and cream. Shortbread and digestives. Malt! Some deep oak and dark chocolate. With time, rich cakes – can’t decide between blueberry cheesecake and orange almond cake. It’s like a pâtisserie set aflame. Rich dried fruits: dates and raisins. With some water – oh my – herbal and floral flavours arise. Lavender-scented biscuits and buttery flowers. Marmalade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; So oily, creamy: very thick. Sharp acidity, with strong character: oranges, lemons and limes. Dried fruits and a splash of wine. Lovely sweetness rounding out the acidity: elegant, like Sauternes. Honey sweetness too. Herbal oak replete with cinnamon, cloves, and other assorted baking spices. With some water, richer chocolate notes, and the peat shines through. Elegant peat: earthy, woody, smoky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Elegant, biscuity peat and billowing smoke. Ash and soot. Those dried fruits, scones, and cheesecakes have been burning for a while now. Rum and raisin ice cream. Incredibly long and filled with smoke. With some water, lemon candy and woody peat. A rich chai latte. Herbal notes, like a strong herbal tea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; A pâtisserie and a fruit stand alight. Heady and aromatic. Supreme Octomore spirit meets supreme Laddie cask wizardry. 92/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/octomore-oba.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="octomore" /><summary type="html">First of the Octomore Concept releases: Octomore OBA Concept 0.1. Bruichladdich will not disclose anything about this except the ABV. Basically: Octomore Black Art.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Port Charlotte (Bruichladdich) 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 13 years 63.5% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-07-port-charlotte-2002-rbt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Port Charlotte (Bruichladdich) 2002 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 13 years 63.5% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-07T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/port-charlotte-2002-rbt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-07-port-charlotte-2002-rbt.html">&lt;p&gt;Early Port Charlotte – the spirit profile was not even a year old as of this run (25 April 2002). Bottled 2016 from cask 7. From the same outturn as the 2002 Bruichladdich, but couldn’t be more different…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Yeah! Funky, vegetal peat. Burning rubber and tire fires. Lit candles dripping with wax and pencil shavings. Dirty smoke. Juicy oranges and their oils. Sandalwood and oak. Second-hand cigar smoke. Blueberry cheesecake. Salty pretzels. There’s a briney note here too that barges in from time to time. Burnt toast with dark roast peanut butter. Roasted almonds. With water, sweeter: caramel and honey. Floral notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Upfront: monumental dirty peat. Vegetal, like the nose. Burning tires. Ash and soot. Medicinal and herbal. Eucalyptus. Then into some oily lemon acidity. Mouth-coating, thick, oily texture. Liquorice and fennel. With time, sweet fruit juice. Pancakes and butter. With water, sweet smoke and ash. Intensely peppery and a little savoury – salt and pepper tofu? Rubbery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Powerful. Dirty smoke. Incense and bonfires. Briney and meaty, mushrooms. Burnt toast. Dark chocolate, roasted hazelnuts, and a sweet, earthy body. Red berries and banana sundaes. Rubbery, herbal. Very long, intensely warming. With water, lemon and orange syrup – acidity balanced by sweetness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Completely different in quality to the 2002 Bruichladdich. Higher ABV but the alcohol is not an impediment at all. Anyway: this stuff is on a tear. For my money, better than any Octomore. 94/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/port-charlotte-2002-rbt.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="port-charlotte" /><category term="rest-and-be-thankful" /><summary type="html">Early Port Charlotte – the spirit profile was not even a year old as of this run (25 April 2002). Bottled 2016 from cask 7. From the same outturn as the 2002 Bruichladdich, but couldn’t be more different…</summary></entry></feed>