<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-05T01:46:33+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Blue Hanger “11th Limited Release” Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd 45.6%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-blue-hanger-11th.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blue Hanger “11th Limited Release” Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd 45.6%" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/blue-hanger-11th</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-blue-hanger-11th.html">&lt;p&gt;Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd’s blended malt whisky. Unknown to me before I tasted: apparently 8 casks in this blend, 4 hoggies, 3 sherry butts. Peated and unpeated Bunnahabhain. Glad to know I wasn’t going insane tasting peat and dried fruits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Pleasingly rubbery, almost Springbank-like. A little peat. Malt-forward, bready. Juicy peaches and pawpaw. Chocolate sundae. Some dried fruits and a hint of oak. Scotch fingers with a gingerbread twist. There’s that little peatsmoke note!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Lighter than expected. A little watery. Malt-forward again, some oak astringency, but quite pleasing. Oak spices. Some brightness, perhaps lemons or a cider. Tea and sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; A very light rubbery peat and fresh grapes. Drying as I write into sultanas and raisins. Via the smoke? Chocolate. Malty and buttery. Butter on toast. A little melon candy. Moderate to long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Terrific nose and pleasing finish, but the palate lets it down. A little watery and simple for my liking. Hollow on the inside. The peat notes are lovely, as are the dried fruits. 77/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="blended-malt" /><category term="berry-bros-rudd" /><summary type="html">Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd’s blended malt whisky. Unknown to me before I tasted: apparently 8 casks in this blend, 4 hoggies, 3 sherry butts. Peated and unpeated Bunnahabhain. Glad to know I wasn’t going insane tasting peat and dried fruits.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Longmorn 2002 “The Ten” LMDW/Signatory Vintage 40.1%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-longmorn-2002-lmdw.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Longmorn 2002 “The Ten” LMDW/Signatory Vintage 40.1%" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/longmorn-2002-lmdw</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-longmorn-2002-lmdw.html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently bottled by Signatory Vintage for La Maison du Whisky as part of “The Ten” series. Label reads: “A distinctive range of 10 young Scotch Whiskies profiling classic characteristics”. Intro range? Anyway, this is Profile #4, “Medium Speyside”. Not sure if Medium is apt…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Sour gummies, honey. Fresh milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; A bit of astringency up front. Actually, a lot. Very watery. Some biscuity notes, then back into astringency, oak. A sugary sweetness. Almost afraid to add water – no matter – eugh. Some grain notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Moderate, alcoholic. Honey. Malt. Chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Inoffensive, but insipid. Was this bottled as a joke? 68/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/lmdw-the-ten-longmorn.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="longmorn" /><category term="lmdw" /><summary type="html">Apparently bottled by Signatory Vintage for La Maison du Whisky as part of “The Ten” series. Label reads: “A distinctive range of 10 young Scotch Whiskies profiling classic characteristics”. Intro range? Anyway, this is Profile #4, “Medium Speyside”. Not sure if Medium is apt…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glen Elgin 2004 Lady of the Glen 16 years 51.3% (Rivesaltes finish)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-glen-elgin-2004-lotg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glen Elgin 2004 Lady of the Glen 16 years 51.3% (Rivesaltes finish)" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glen-elgin-2004-lotg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-glen-elgin-2004-lotg.html">&lt;p&gt;Fifteen years in a hogshead, finished in a Rivesaltes cask and then charged into a rather attractive bottle. Rivesaltes is a French sweet fortified. And that cask did a number on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Dark amber, ruby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Yes please. Treacle and honey. Cinnamon buns. Buttery panettone stuffed to the brim with candied orange peel and raisins. A keen edge of sweet acidity: lemon candies and apple juice. Cinnamon and vanilla. Aromatic and moreish. Skip dessert on the nose alone. Pepitas and marzipan. If you look for it, there is malt, granola, and bread and butter pudding. Much easier with water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Syrupy and thick. Maple syrup over pancakes, cream. Strong notes of muscat. There’s that heady sweetness, tempered by a whack of acidity. Raisins and dates soaked in orange juice and some lemons. More acidic as the palate continues, and into cinnamon, white pepper, and cayenne. With a bit of water, the fruit juiciness intensifies, and a touch of the malt reveals itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Lemon candy, treacle. Gluhwein with vanilla sugar. Long, boozy, like a rum-soaked pudding. Dark chocolate and a waft of mint. Dried fruits (how quaint). A touch of chartreuse. Jaffa cakes. With water, museli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Very wine forward, to put it politely. For some that may be a downside, it takes a splash of water and a keen lookout (or keen imagination) to reveal the underlying spirit. Though some don’t drink a whisky without an aggressive cask. Either way, the character imparted is just lovely. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/lotg-glen-elgin-16-rivesaltes.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glen-elgin" /><category term="lotg" /><summary type="html">Fifteen years in a hogshead, finished in a Rivesaltes cask and then charged into a rather attractive bottle. Rivesaltes is a French sweet fortified. And that cask did a number on this one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dailuaine 2007 Douglas Laing’s Provenance 9 years 46% (sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-dailuaine-2007-provenance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dailuaine 2007 Douglas Laing’s Provenance 9 years 46% (sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/dailuaine-2007-provenance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-dailuaine-2007-provenance.html">&lt;p&gt;Kind of obscure Diageo malt, which means they’ve got a Flora and Fauna bottle. Instead of a cute animal this one is from Douglas Laing’s Provenance lineup and was aged in a sherry butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Fresh pears and caramel. Bready, malty. Lighty scented with dried fruits – well integrated sherry. Gingerbread. Scones with jam and cream. Oak, and oak spices. Sugared biscuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Dried fruits and milk chocolate digestives. A touch of the spice drawer, but mostly chilli. Thinner but lightly milky mouthfeel… Skim milky? Almond milky? The thinness is doing it a disservice now… A bit of herbaceous oak at the end. Astringency. Doesn’t really give anything else up with water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Milk chocolate and spices. Full cream milk. A little tannic (huh?). Moderate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Pleasant, everyday, minimal thought required malt. Nose is by far the most interesting, everything else is serviceable. 80/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/provenance-dailuaine.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="dailuaine" /><category term="douglas-laing" /><category term="provenance" /><summary type="html">Kind of obscure Diageo malt, which means they’ve got a Flora and Fauna bottle. Instead of a cute animal this one is from Douglas Laing’s Provenance lineup and was aged in a sherry butt.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Tobermory “Manzanilla Finish” 12 years 46.3% (exbourbon and manzanilla)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-tobermory-12-manzanilla.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tobermory “Manzanilla Finish” 12 years 46.3% (exbourbon and manzanilla)" /><published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/tobermory-12-manzanilla</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-tobermory-12-manzanilla.html">&lt;p&gt;Official bottling from Tobermory. From what I gather, spent ten years in exbourbon casks and two in manzanilla casks. For those playing at home, manzanilla is a dry sherry similar to a fino, known for its freshness and salinity. Unusual, as most sherry casks used for whisky are oloroso or PX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Leather, old boots. Pepper and chilli flakes. Yeasty funk (flor?). Chinese red dates: jujube. Salty, briny. Seashells and the beach. Heavy treacle and cream. Heady aroma, Manuka honey. Grassy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Malt, then into fig and dates. Brightness. There’s that leathery, briny, Tobermory funk. Salted caramel and vanilla slice. Boozy! Milky texture. Back to berry jams. Pretty spicy. A little winey. Lemons and a bit of grain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy and jammy. Milky and malty notes. A little woody, some cocktail bitters. Moderate. Those jammy and milky notes last for quite a while.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Tobermory funk is polarising, but I’m a lover. Real quality stuff, quite complex. Wish the finish was a bit fuller, but the nose is great. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/tobermory-12.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="tobermory" /><summary type="html">Official bottling from Tobermory. From what I gather, spent ten years in exbourbon casks and two in manzanilla casks. For those playing at home, manzanilla is a dry sherry similar to a fino, known for its freshness and salinity. Unusual, as most sherry casks used for whisky are oloroso or PX.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Deanston 2009 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 10 years 57.1% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-deanston-2009-rbt.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Deanston 2009 Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful 10 years 57.1% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/deanston-2009-rbt</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-deanston-2009-rbt.html">&lt;p&gt;Here’s a recent bottle from Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful (great story behind that name). I’m personally enjoying what Deanston has to offer these days. Read on if you like oranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Strawberry milk. Lactic — interesting! Rosemary oils and fruit jellies. Chalky, oranges.  More oranges. Sweet biscuits. White chocolate and almonds. Lollipops. A little floral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Sweet and citric. Orange and tangerine forward. Bright acidity, white wine vinegar. A little chalky, like orange sherbet? Then there’s the malt. Still bright, sharp! Sweet pastries. Very heady, boozy. Strong!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Orange candies. Long, eucalyptus. A little milky, lactic at the end. Caramel. Orange juice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Orange candy and jellies in a bottle! A bit of some lactic funk. Love what Deanston is doing and what RBT is bottling. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/deanston-rbt.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="deanston" /><category term="rest-and-be-thankful" /><summary type="html">Here’s a recent bottle from Rest &amp;amp; Be Thankful (great story behind that name). I’m personally enjoying what Deanston has to offer these days. Read on if you like oranges.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Caol Ila “Unpeated Style” 18 years 59.8% (refill exbourbon hogsheads)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-caol-ila-18-unpeated-2017.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Caol Ila “Unpeated Style” 18 years 59.8% (refill exbourbon hogsheads)" /><published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/caol-ila-18-unpeated-2017</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-caol-ila-18-unpeated-2017.html">&lt;p&gt;Picture this: Caol Ila. Now remove the peat. Hard, no? Let’s see. This one was bottled in 2017 for Diageo’s special releases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; A heady attack of citrus peels and their oils. Tea tree oil and eucalyptus. A little vegetal. Very austere, tight. With water, lemon curd and English breakfast tea with milk. Watermelon. Scones with cream. Minerality. Better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Woah! Caramel comes through, with a big whack of malt. Herbal. With water, some fennel and rockmelon. But emphasis on the sweet, fruits. Very powerful stuff. Full and oily mouthfeel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Quite hot. White chocolate and lemon peel. Bright. A little oily. Sticks around in your mouth for a long time, giving off all those zesty and citric notes. Eucalyptus. A little woody. Rubber? Very powerful. Very long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Straightforward and powerful malt. Lemons and herbs and variations thereof. Uncomplicated. Very warming. Really needs water. Length of the finish is a highlight. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/caol-ila-unpeated.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="caol-ila" /><summary type="html">Picture this: Caol Ila. Now remove the peat. Hard, no? Let’s see. This one was bottled in 2017 for Diageo’s special releases.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ben Nevis 1996 The Whisky Agency 23 years 47.6% (hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-ben-nevis-1996-twa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ben Nevis 1996 The Whisky Agency 23 years 47.6% (hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ben-nevis-1996-twa</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-ben-nevis-1996-twa.html">&lt;p&gt;Back to back Ben Nevis. This time from The Whisky Agency. Presumably a sherry hogshead, but not specified beyond cask size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Scented candlewax. Olive oil. Apricots. Apricot delight. Liquorice. Strawberry liquorice. Boozy fruit mince tarts. Christmas pudding. Very fruity. Brown sugar and ginger. Salted caramel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Malt forward. Raisins and sultanas with some brightness. Very herbaceous, coriander and mint. Malty, porridge and museli notes. Menthol candies, breath mints. Oranges and orange peel. Sweet, boiled lollies and berry soda. There’s a bit of that oil again!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Malty, syrupy. Grapefruit and mint syrup (I was experimenting with syrups a while ago…). Sultanas and honey. Quite long. Great balance between malt and sweetness. Some wax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Lovely dram. Love this a lot more than the Thompson Bros. Balanced on the head of a pin: great distillate playing nicely with sherry. Loving the wax and oil. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/ben-nevis-twa.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ben-nevis" /><category term="the-whisky-agency" /><summary type="html">Back to back Ben Nevis. This time from The Whisky Agency. Presumably a sherry hogshead, but not specified beyond cask size.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ben Nevis 1996 Thompson Bros. 22 years 44.4% (refill sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-ben-nevis-1996-thompson-bros.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ben Nevis 1996 Thompson Bros. 22 years 44.4% (refill sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ben-nevis-1996-thompson-bros</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-03-ben-nevis-1996-thompson-bros.html">&lt;p&gt;From cult indie bottler comes a cult distillery in a cult cask. At a cult price too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Candlewax, scented candles. Sand and wet earth. Dried fruits and pineapple. Cereal and malt, honey over porridge. Pear sauce. Fresh strawberries. Treacle. Very much sherried, but not overpowering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Sweet dried fruits and loads of honey. Waxy notes. Baking spices: cinnamon and vanilla bean. Fresh wood, almost green. A little bit of olive oil and chilli. Malty. Museli and milk. Matcha?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Cream and vanilla, sugar and Pinot Noir. Raisins, sultanas. Quite spicy, but not sharp. Wax again. Moderate. Wish it was longer. More dried fruits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Interesting stuff. Waxy, might have guessed Clynelish or Teaninich. Understated sherry, which is appreciated, but I wish the finish was longer. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/ben-nevis-thompson-bros.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ben-nevis" /><category term="thompson-bros" /><summary type="html">From cult indie bottler comes a cult distillery in a cult cask. At a cult price too!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Teaninich 2006 Hidden Spirits 13 years 51.7% (exbourbon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-teaninich-2006-hidden-spirits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Teaninich 2006 Hidden Spirits 13 years 51.7% (exbourbon)" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/teaninich-2006-hidden-spirits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-02-teaninich-2006-hidden-spirits.html">&lt;p&gt;Another Hidden Spirit, this time from Teaninich. Not quite as obscure as Balmenach, but not exactly hyped… hope you like salad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Huge malt. big banana. Candlewax? Watermelon, rockmelon. Stone fruits. A bit of a fruit platter here. Cucumber and a bit of salt. A little meaty after some time. Very full. With a bit of water, reveals floral notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Woah. Light Cucumber and caramel. Watermelon and salt. Fresh melons and lemonade icy-poles. Caramel and toffee, brown sugar. Malt, corn flakes. Cucumber again! What’s going on? With water, sweeter, sugar cookies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Perfumed. Dried fruits. Chai lattes and apples. Fresh salad (cucumber…). Very long, very pleasant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Haha, so weird. Cucumber and salad? Melons and meat? Typical fresh fruits and caramel? Wild stuff. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/teaninich-hisp.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="teaninich" /><category term="hidden-spirits" /><summary type="html">Another Hidden Spirit, this time from Teaninich. Not quite as obscure as Balmenach, but not exactly hyped… hope you like salad.</summary></entry></feed>