<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-05T22:35:03+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Ledaig 2010 Chorlton 10 years 57% (bourbon barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-ledaig-2010-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ledaig 2010 Chorlton 10 years 57% (bourbon barrel)" /><published>2021-05-04T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/ledaig-2010-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-ledaig-2010-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Final dram of the Chorlton night. Ledaig, of Tobermory fame. Or should that be Tobermory, of Ledaig fame? Anyway, absolute heavyweight. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final bit of Chorlton trivia: David bottles all of his stuff to his own tastes. From the source: highland style or peated, no odd finishes or wine casks. Very orthodox stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Fish oil. Meaty. Dirty, rubbery, oily, phenolic peat and smoke. Spices, but not the typical: chilli, cayenne, black pepper, fennel. Dehydrated apples and apricots (cocktail garnishes!). Cherries and lychees, berry coulis. Acute minerality. Vanilla caramel and roasted hazelnuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Brown sugar sweetness on the attack. Then into dirty peat. Rubber, tire fires. Vegetation. Ash and soot. But then into cream, full woodiness. Floral. Grassy. Balances well with the umami on the nose. Dirt again. Smoked pears. Malt. A little nutty, peanuts? The peat’s back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Excuse the poetry: you’re on the beach, and you’ve lit a little peat fire in your heart. Deeply warming. Coastal, salty. Belching smoke and dirty peat. Chocolate and peanuts: Whittaker’s Peanut Slab. A little citric at the very end. Very long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Filthy peat and belching smoke. A heavy truck passing by. A campfire on the beach. A complete pleasure to drink. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="ledaig" /><category term="tobermory" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Final dram of the Chorlton night. Ledaig, of Tobermory fame. Or should that be Tobermory, of Ledaig fame? Anyway, absolute heavyweight. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Lochindaal (Bruichladdich) 2007 Chorlton 12 years 61.9% (bourbon barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-lochindaal-2007-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Lochindaal (Bruichladdich) 2007 Chorlton 12 years 61.9% (bourbon barrel)" /><published>2021-05-04T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/lochindaal-2007-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-lochindaal-2007-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Lochindaal was a peated spirit made by Bruichladdich shortly after they opened. More heavily peated than Port Charlotte. David says that it’s more like a peated Laddie spirit – it’s got that clarity we’d associate with it. I agree with him. Unfortunately, Bruichladdich is no longer making Lochindaal. Perhaps not a lost distillery, but a lost malt! Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Chorlton trivia: David runs the thing by himself, and got started by running his own tastings in Chorlton, Manchester. Then he bottled some cask ends, and the rest is history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Vanilla custard. Medicinal – elevated cough syrup. Umami: meaty and mushroomy. Seaweed and seawater near the beach. Very clean, austere spirit, very much akin to regular Bruichladdich. Fennel and aniseed. Honeyed and floral. A small yeasty, lactic, funky note. Salty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Deeply medicinal. Definitely elevated cough syrup. Syrupy in texture too, thick. Earthy, woody peat. Raspberry jellies, strawberries and cream. Jam and scones. Honey and fennel, carrying with it some ginger. A little acidity, lime juice. Herbal malt. Some citrus peel – don’t forget the pith. Oily. Smoke – and quite a lot of it at the tail end, leading into the finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Mouth-filling smoke. It’s got volume. Very long. Warming. Ashy and earthy. Creamy. Tropical fruits: mangoes and bananas. Ice cream sundae. Very clear. Full, powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Creamy, smoky, medicinal spirit with a keen edge. Swims well. The bones are Bruichladdich. I simply cannot say anything bad about this malt. 92/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="lochindaal" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Lochindaal was a peated spirit made by Bruichladdich shortly after they opened. More heavily peated than Port Charlotte. David says that it’s more like a peated Laddie spirit – it’s got that clarity we’d associate with it. I agree with him. Unfortunately, Bruichladdich is no longer making Lochindaal. Perhaps not a lost distillery, but a lost malt! Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Orkney 2005 Chorlton 15 years 57.1% (refill bourbon hogshead, apparently)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-orkney-2005-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Orkney 2005 Chorlton 15 years 57.1% (refill bourbon hogshead, apparently)" /><published>2021-05-04T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/orkney-2005-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-orkney-2005-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;A lot of secret Orkney casks lately. No surprises: Highland Park! Are they having a sale or something? And what’s with this cask? Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Chorlton trivia: apparently a lot of his casks are now held at Dalswinton Bond, a dunnage warehouse. Smells good, I imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Dark gold, ruby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Wow. Exbourbon? No way. Sautéed mushrooms and soy sauce. Really quite thick, brothy, fatty. Stinky cheese. Balsamic vinegar – woody sweetness and acidity together. Salt and vinegar chips. Tart apples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Malty. A big whack of red fruits, berries. Syrupy dried fruits and apricot delight. It’s a bit like a sherry cask. Slightly medicinal peat. Very herbal. We’ve added a bit too much cinnamon to our milk. Thick.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Medicinal peaty finish. Heavy. Off-profile for a Highland Park. Probably why it was independently bottled. Smoke. Coastal saltiness. Tamari almonds. Mushrooms and soy sauce again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Completely mental. Big, heavy, coastal malt. Clarity of the umami notes are a highlight. If you told me this was an Islay, maybe refill sherry, I’d believe you. Completely off-profile for both the (ostensible) cask and the distillery. 90/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="orkney" /><category term="highland-park" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">A lot of secret Orkney casks lately. No surprises: Highland Park! Are they having a sale or something? And what’s with this cask? Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunnahabhain 2002 Chorlton 18 years 53.4% (sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-bunnahabhain-2002-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunnahabhain 2002 Chorlton 18 years 53.4% (sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-04T20:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T20:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bunnahabhain-2002-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-bunnahabhain-2002-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;A Christmas release for Chorlton. Apt. Sherry, but the complete opposite of a sherry bomb. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More Chorlton trivia: David is buying more stock, thinking about the future. As for the past, cask prices have increased a lot over the last two years. Speculation has apparently played a role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Banana caramel milkshake. Chewy toffee. Coastal – a little salty, earthy – more sandy. Red apples, candied apples. A waft of dried fruits and spots of milk chocolate. Quite rich, which is appropriate for a Christmas release. A touch of wax. Oak spices. A splash of sherry vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Big raisin and sultana smack. but quite understated sherry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understated sherry. Entrance with classic dried fruits: raisins and sultanas. Rounded by oak spices, cinnamon, and cloves. Sweetness balanced by a touch of astringency, stemmy notes. Fruit mince tarts and panforte. Let’s riff with this Christmas theme. Oak spices, cinnamon, cloves. Thick, creamy texture. Every now and then, a pop of tart berry acidity. Interesting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Primarily spicy and fruity. A little tannic and tart. Not hot at all, but quite heady. Dark chocolate and coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Probably the most average bottle of the night. That said, still very high quality, and absolutely spot-on the Christmas theme. An elegant Christmas, to be sure, given the understatement of the cask. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bunnahabhain" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">A Christmas release for Chorlton. Apt. Sherry, but the complete opposite of a sherry bomb. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glenlossie 1992 Chorlton 27 years 51.2% (hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-glenlossie-1992-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glenlossie 1992 Chorlton 27 years 51.2% (hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-04T20:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T20:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glenlossie-1992-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-glenlossie-1992-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Early 90s Glenlossie. Reportedly (from David Bennett) amazing, underrated, the golden years. Also, I’m told, needs this kind of age. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another bit of Chorlton trivia. How does David actually buy casks. Several ways, reportedly: direct cask sales, through cask brokers, or minimum purchases (parcels). Parcels might be split with other bottlers or put down for later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Strawberry liquorice. Cherries and chocolate: cherry ripe. Heapings of red berries. Acidity too: berry tartness. A drop of olive oil on the nose (semi-jokingly: late harvest). A little salty. A touch metallic – pleasing! With water: mint is back. Brown sugar. With time: waxy, potato chips, quite bready.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Beeswax, honey (David: absolutely). Hyper-floral. A little earthy, but not dirty. Petrichor? Orchard fruits. Very sweet, but not sugary, elegant. Wafers and digestive biscuits. With water, more wax! Honeyed and a hint of basil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Very full sweetness. Pears and honey. Regal. Strawberry jams, quite thick. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Elegant stuff. Pure spring and summer malt. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glenlossie" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Early 90s Glenlossie. Reportedly (from David Bennett) amazing, underrated, the golden years. Also, I’m told, needs this kind of age. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Croftengea (Loch Lomond) 2007 Chorlton 13 years 53.9% (hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-croftengea-2007-chorlton.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Croftengea (Loch Lomond) 2007 Chorlton 13 years 53.9% (hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-04T20:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T20:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/croftengea-2007-chorlton</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-croftengea-2007-chorlton.html">&lt;p&gt;Croftengea is one of Loch Lomond’s many spirit profiles. Heavily peated. This one, not so much. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team. First cab off the rank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First bit of Chorlton trivia. The labels for this series feature medieval art about how to live a healthy life. Apt in the middle of a pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Kouign amman. Vanilla crème pâtissière. Blueberry yoghurt – fruity and a little lactic. A little herbal and woody – rosemary bushes. Hot chocolate with a twist of cloves and mint. Mint slices – minty and rosemary oil. Fresh, creamy. Lemon peel oil. After some time and water, a whack of pears.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Herbaceous, grassy. Milky texture, bordering on creamy. Malt forward. Sweet caramel milk: Caramello Koalas. Lightly peated? To be honest, it seems unpeated. Spicy and a hot. David Bennett mentions banana milkshakes and a bit of peat in the background. If the peat’s there, it’s more of a roasty, chocolatey note. With time, the herbaceous, grassy notes intensify. Light citrus, quite floral.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Caramel milk again! Spicy and quite warming. Herbaceous finish with a hint of smoke. Almonds. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Fresh, a certain aperitif quality as David emphasises. Surprising Croftengea, if you told me it was unpeated I would believe you. Which is surprising for a heavily peated malt. Complete oddity. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="croftengea" /><category term="loch-lomond" /><category term="chorlton" /><summary type="html">Croftengea is one of Loch Lomond’s many spirit profiles. Heavily peated. This one, not so much. Tasted virtually with David Bennett (Chorlton) and the Whisky and Alement team. First cab off the rank.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Longmorn 2002 “The Ten” LMDW/Signatory Vintage 40.1%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-longmorn-2002-lmdw.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Longmorn 2002 “The Ten” LMDW/Signatory Vintage 40.1%" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/longmorn-2002-lmdw</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-longmorn-2002-lmdw.html">&lt;p&gt;Apparently bottled by Signatory Vintage for La Maison du Whisky as part of “The Ten” series. Label reads: “A distinctive range of 10 young Scotch Whiskies profiling classic characteristics”. Intro range? Anyway, this is Profile #4, “Medium Speyside”. Not sure if Medium is apt…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Sour gummies, honey. Fresh milk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; A bit of astringency up front. Actually, a lot. Very watery. Some biscuity notes, then back into astringency, oak. A sugary sweetness. Almost afraid to add water – no matter – eugh. Some grain notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Moderate, alcoholic. Honey. Malt. Chocolate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Inoffensive, but insipid. Was this bottled as a joke? 68/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/lmdw-the-ten-longmorn.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="longmorn" /><category term="lmdw" /><summary type="html">Apparently bottled by Signatory Vintage for La Maison du Whisky as part of “The Ten” series. Label reads: “A distinctive range of 10 young Scotch Whiskies profiling classic characteristics”. Intro range? Anyway, this is Profile #4, “Medium Speyside”. Not sure if Medium is apt…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glen Elgin 2004 Lady of the Glen 16 years 51.3% (Rivesaltes finish)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-glen-elgin-2004-lotg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glen Elgin 2004 Lady of the Glen 16 years 51.3% (Rivesaltes finish)" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glen-elgin-2004-lotg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-glen-elgin-2004-lotg.html">&lt;p&gt;Fifteen years in a hogshead, finished in a Rivesaltes cask and then charged into a rather attractive bottle. Rivesaltes is a French sweet fortified. And that cask did a number on this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Dark amber, ruby&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Yes please. Treacle and honey. Cinnamon buns. Buttery panettone stuffed to the brim with candied orange peel and raisins. A keen edge of sweet acidity: lemon candies and apple juice. Cinnamon and vanilla. Aromatic and moreish. Skip dessert on the nose alone. Pepitas and marzipan. If you look for it, there is malt, granola, and bread and butter pudding. Much easier with water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Syrupy and thick. Maple syrup over pancakes, cream. Strong notes of muscat. There’s that heady sweetness, tempered by a whack of acidity. Raisins and dates soaked in orange juice and some lemons. More acidic as the palate continues, and into cinnamon, white pepper, and cayenne. With a bit of water, the fruit juiciness intensifies, and a touch of the malt reveals itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Lemon candy, treacle. Gluhwein with vanilla sugar. Long, boozy, like a rum-soaked pudding. Dark chocolate and a waft of mint. Dried fruits (how quaint). A touch of chartreuse. Jaffa cakes. With water, museli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Very wine forward, to put it politely. For some that may be a downside, it takes a splash of water and a keen lookout (or keen imagination) to reveal the underlying spirit. Though some don’t drink a whisky without an aggressive cask. Either way, the character imparted is just lovely. 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/lotg-glen-elgin-16-rivesaltes.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glen-elgin" /><category term="lotg" /><summary type="html">Fifteen years in a hogshead, finished in a Rivesaltes cask and then charged into a rather attractive bottle. Rivesaltes is a French sweet fortified. And that cask did a number on this one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dailuaine 2007 Douglas Laing’s Provenance 9 years 46% (sherry butt)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-dailuaine-2007-provenance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dailuaine 2007 Douglas Laing’s Provenance 9 years 46% (sherry butt)" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/dailuaine-2007-provenance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-dailuaine-2007-provenance.html">&lt;p&gt;Kind of obscure Diageo malt, which means they’ve got a Flora and Fauna bottle. Instead of a cute animal this one is from Douglas Laing’s Provenance lineup and was aged in a sherry butt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Fresh pears and caramel. Bready, malty. Lighty scented with dried fruits – well integrated sherry. Gingerbread. Scones with jam and cream. Oak, and oak spices. Sugared biscuits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Dried fruits and milk chocolate digestives. A touch of the spice drawer, but mostly chilli. Thinner but lightly milky mouthfeel… Skim milky? Almond milky? The thinness is doing it a disservice now… A bit of herbaceous oak at the end. Astringency. Doesn’t really give anything else up with water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Milk chocolate and spices. Full cream milk. A little tannic (huh?). Moderate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Pleasant, everyday, minimal thought required malt. Nose is by far the most interesting, everything else is serviceable. 80/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/provenance-dailuaine.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="dailuaine" /><category term="douglas-laing" /><category term="provenance" /><summary type="html">Kind of obscure Diageo malt, which means they’ve got a Flora and Fauna bottle. Instead of a cute animal this one is from Douglas Laing’s Provenance lineup and was aged in a sherry butt.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blue Hanger “11th Limited Release” Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd 45.6%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-blue-hanger-11th.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blue Hanger “11th Limited Release” Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd 45.6%" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/blue-hanger-11th</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-04-blue-hanger-11th.html">&lt;p&gt;Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd’s blended malt whisky. Unknown to me before I tasted: apparently 8 casks in this blend, 4 hoggies, 3 sherry butts. Peated and unpeated Bunnahabhain. Glad to know I wasn’t going insane tasting peat and dried fruits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Pleasingly rubbery, almost Springbank-like. A little peat. Malt-forward, bready. Juicy peaches and pawpaw. Chocolate sundae. Some dried fruits and a hint of oak. Scotch fingers with a gingerbread twist. There’s that little peatsmoke note!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Lighter than expected. A little watery. Malt-forward again, some oak astringency, but quite pleasing. Oak spices. Some brightness, perhaps lemons or a cider. Tea and sugar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; A very light rubbery peat and fresh grapes. Drying as I write into sultanas and raisins. Via the smoke? Chocolate. Malty and buttery. Butter on toast. A little melon candy. Moderate to long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Terrific nose and pleasing finish, but the palate lets it down. A little watery and simple for my liking. Hollow on the inside. The peat notes are lovely, as are the dried fruits. 77/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="blended-malt" /><category term="berry-bros-rudd" /><summary type="html">Berry Bros. &amp;amp; Rudd’s blended malt whisky. Unknown to me before I tasted: apparently 8 casks in this blend, 4 hoggies, 3 sherry butts. Peated and unpeated Bunnahabhain. Glad to know I wasn’t going insane tasting peat and dried fruits.</summary></entry></feed>