<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-14T00:32:10+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Tamdhu 2006 Douglas Laing 11 years 48.4% (refill hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-13-tamdhu-2006-dl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Tamdhu 2006 Douglas Laing 11 years 48.4% (refill hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-13T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-13T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/tamdhu-2006-dl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-13-tamdhu-2006-dl.html">&lt;p&gt;The next Old Particular – Tamdhu! The Can-dhu spirit (TM)! Love that little marketing line. Reference DL12577. Anyway, this one’s bare: not a hint of sherry…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Juicy. Fruity white wine and fresh grapes. Very bright. Quite sweet, too. Stewed apples and cinnamon. There’s a leafiness to this, half floral, half, well, leafy. Honey and lemon tea. With a little bit of water this turns into a complete caramel monster! Tiramisu! Papaya! Cream and macadamia nuts. some desiccated coconut. Ginger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Creamy and loaded with lemons. Into the malt, thick, a drizzle of honey. Quite sweet, caramel, almost like a candy bar! Twix? A bubblegum fruitiness too. Dried pawpaw. Some coconut. Tropical!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy: cinnamon and cloves. Vanilla and whipped cream. Waffles. Honey, malty, pancakes. Tropical fruits: bananas, papaya, mangoes. Long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; So lovely to drink a refill hoggy Tamdhu! Fresh sweetness with a tropical spin. Malty and great acidity. Everything works so well. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/tamdhu-2006-dl.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="tamdhu" /><category term="douglas-laing" /><category term="old-particular" /><summary type="html">The next Old Particular – Tamdhu! The Can-dhu spirit (TM)! Love that little marketing line. Reference DL12577. Anyway, this one’s bare: not a hint of sherry…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bunnahabhain 2007 Douglas Laing 12 years 48.4% (refill hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-13-bunnahabhain-2007-dl.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bunnahabhain 2007 Douglas Laing 12 years 48.4% (refill hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-13T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-13T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bunnahabhain-2007-dl</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-13-bunnahabhain-2007-dl.html">&lt;p&gt;Refill hoggy Bunnahabhain from Douglas Laing’s Old Particular series. Cask reference DL13777.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Big whack of malt. Then into bananas, caramel… banana sundae. Cinnamon, vanilla, muesli. Salty and briney: coastal. Apples and pears stewing away. With water: some banana skins? There’s a very slight rubbery scent. Very pleasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Sweet and lightly herbal malt. Creamy texture. Bananas and caramel are back again – definitely a banana cream sundae. Easy drinking. Salted caramel, dulce de leche. A waft of coconut, a little jammy and some sponge cake: lamingtons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Warming. Surprise! Bananas and caramel. Will it ever end? Hope not. Shortbread, perhaps some cheesecake. Creamy and thick. Malty. A tinge of coffee and textured milk. A little grassy. Quite long. With water, the softest hint of rubber, perhaps ash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Malt forward. Eating a banana caramel sundae at the beach. Very pleasant. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bunnahabhain-2007-dl.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bunnahabhain" /><category term="douglas-laing" /><category term="old-particular" /><summary type="html">Refill hoggy Bunnahabhain from Douglas Laing’s Old Particular series. Cask reference DL13777.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linkwood 2011 Lady of the Glen 10 years 57.8% (Marsala finish)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-12-linkwood-2011-lotg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linkwood 2011 Lady of the Glen 10 years 57.8% (Marsala finish)" /><published>2021-05-12T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-12T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/linkwood-2011-lotg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-12-linkwood-2011-lotg.html">&lt;p&gt;Linkwood! How could I say no? Eight years in a hogshead followed by two in a Marsala barrique from Vino Marsala in Sicily. Blackcurrants are mentioned on the bottle, and I must agree…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; This one has depth. Berry coulis – perhaps even berry sorbet? Brightness, too. I’ve gone to the gelataria and gotten a scoop of lemon sorbet, strawberry sorbet, and perhaps a chocolate gelato. Esters. Balsamic vinegar. Tart apples and cherries. A bit of brown sugar. A slight cheesy, umami funk to it too. A little bit of minerality, saltiness. Finally, a waft of greenness – I’d like to say floral, given it’s a Linkwood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Juicy! Apple and blackcurrant juice. Tart and bright. Wine-driven sweetness. Pain aux raisins. The alcohol here is so well integrated. The malt is terrific too. It’s not hidden – I wouldn’t say it’s centre stage, but certainly integral. There’s a spot of lovely, rounding oak and tannins at the end. With water, citrus oils and a bit of eucalyptus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Gluhwein and tiramisu (who would have thought…?). Oak and oak spices. Cinnamon and vanilla. Jam on toast. Still have echoes of that juiciness: blackcurrants are back with a vengeance. Ribena! Perfumed and long, very winey. Warming and ever so lightly nutty: toasted hazelnuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Terrific stuff. Juicy, bright, and wine-forward. The malt is not drowned and plays an important role. Alcohol is well integrated. Nothing bad to say. 89/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/linkwood-2011-lotg.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="linkwood" /><category term="lotg" /><summary type="html">Linkwood! How could I say no? Eight years in a hogshead followed by two in a Marsala barrique from Vino Marsala in Sicily. Blackcurrants are mentioned on the bottle, and I must agree…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glen Moray 2008 Lady of the Glen 12 years 57.1% (first fill exbourbon barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-12-glen-moray-2008-lotg.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glen Moray 2008 Lady of the Glen 12 years 57.1% (first fill exbourbon barrel)" /><published>2021-05-12T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-12T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glen-moray-2008-lotg</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-12-glen-moray-2008-lotg.html">&lt;p&gt;First fill exbourbon! Full term. I’m expecting something sweet…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Yellow gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Toasted coconut. Vanilla and caramel. Toffee. As expected: very sweet! The cask has done its job. Golden syrup over pancakes, a side of whipped cream. Banana lollies. Creamy malt. Popcorn. Soft cookies with a bit of cinnamon. Melting butter. With water: a cake-like sweetness. Banoffee tart. Some fresh orchard fruits. This one swims very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; An immediate explosion of toffee, caramel, sugar – you name it – sweetness. Very creamy. A citrus acidity too on the attack: oranges, lemons. Accompanied by a lightly fruity sweetness: fresh grapes? Cinnamon and cloves, oak spices. With water, the malt reveals itself. Very clear! Sweet biscuits and a light note of tropical fruits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Orange and apple juice and a bit of mint. Quite hot, spicy. Whole tubs of vanilla custard and assorted pastries. Malty. Strawberries and cream. A touch of coconut. With water, a whack of peppermint to go alongside the vanilla.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Very much a dessert dram, I think. Driven by grain and sugar, not fruit or wine. Otherwise conventional and honest malt. Definitely benefits from a splash of water. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/glen-moray-2008-lotg.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glen-moray" /><category term="lotg" /><summary type="html">First fill exbourbon! Full term. I’m expecting something sweet…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bruichladdich “Islay Barley” 2010 50% (exbourbon and wine casks)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-11-bruichladdich-islay-barley-2010.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bruichladdich “Islay Barley” 2010 50% (exbourbon and wine casks)" /><published>2021-05-11T21:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-11T21:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bruichladdich-islay-barley-2010</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-11-bruichladdich-islay-barley-2010.html">&lt;p&gt;One of Bruichladdich’s uber-provenance/terroir bottlings. Distilled from Optic and Oxbridge barley grown on the following farms: Coull, Cruach, Dunlossit, Island, Mulindry, Rockside, Starchmill, and Sunderland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Sweet honey. Floral. Lactic, yoghurty funk. Very Bruichladdich. There’s a freshness to it, leafy, stemmy. Fresh white wine acidity, cream. Muesli with dried paw paw and the odd raisin. Jam and scones. Buttery and rich. With a bit of water, definitely creamier and more herbal notes – coriander, black pepper – shine through. It’s very clean, refreshing. A little bit of minerality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Creamy and thick but light in character. It’s very bright – lemon acidity – perhaps a tad too bright. Driven by sweet honey and floral notes, then into a lightly spiced malt. It’s nutty – think particularly fatty ones like cashews and macadamia nuts. Those nuts caramelised with honey. With water, the texture becomes silkier, and we get waves of crystal clear malt. It’s a little floral, herbaceous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy, cinnamon, cayenne, and a bit of peppermint. Menthol. Malty and a little oak to it. Dark chocolate infused with chilli. A hint of swiss cheese and fresh ricotta. Quite long, warming, and interestingly, spicy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Solid stuff. Very clean malt, quite angular. Perhaps that acidic note went too far, but I very much appreciate the laddie funk and the spicy, floral notes. 85/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bruichladdich-islay-barley-2010.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bruichladdich" /><summary type="html">One of Bruichladdich’s uber-provenance/terroir bottlings. Distilled from Optic and Oxbridge barley grown on the following farms: Coull, Cruach, Dunlossit, Island, Mulindry, Rockside, Starchmill, and Sunderland.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Clynelish 1995 Signatory Vintage 20 years 43%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-clynelish-1995-sv.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Clynelish 1995 Signatory Vintage 20 years 43%" /><published>2021-05-09T21:50:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:50:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/clynelish-1995-sv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-clynelish-1995-sv.html">&lt;p&gt;Nice bottle. Part of Signatory’s “Decanter Collection”. A lot of what I assume to be floccing in the bottle, so unlikely to be chill filtered, even at 43 per cent ABV. Bottled in 2016, before Clynelish got weird about people using their name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Amber.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Wax and apples. Classic Clynelish. Pain aux raisins. Caramel. A whack of perfume — well integrated. Melon skins. Ice cream sundaes: fatty. A bit fresh: tomato and cucumber. Some almonds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Milky texture. Orchard fruits and boiled lollies. Candlewax. Orange peel. Cinnamon and other assorted baking spices. Malty! Texture is unfortunately thinning… now we’ve got some red berries, some stemminess. A little bit of oak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy — oak spices. Cinnamon and cloves. Orchard fruits and wax. A hint of tropical fruits — creamy bananas. Coconut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Disappointing. Proof does it no favours. Classic flavours but dialed down. 82/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/clynelish-1995-sv.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="clynelish" /><category term="signatory-vintage" /><summary type="html">Nice bottle. Part of Signatory’s “Decanter Collection”. A lot of what I assume to be floccing in the bottle, so unlikely to be chill filtered, even at 43 per cent ABV. Bottled in 2016, before Clynelish got weird about people using their name.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Glen Flagler “Rare All-Malt Scotch” 5 years 40%</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-glen-flagler-5.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Glen Flagler “Rare All-Malt Scotch” 5 years 40%" /><published>2021-05-09T21:40:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:40:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/glen-flagler-5</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-glen-flagler-5.html">&lt;p&gt;Silent distillery. Bottling apparently for the Italian market. Parafilmed and everything!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw. Unlikely any colouring here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Waxy and vegetal. Rather perfumed. Orchard fruits: pears, apples, ripe. Carrots and celery. Candied apples, boiled sweets. Lemon and limes. Citrus peels and their oils.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; A little watery – probably the ABV. Great herbal notes. Lemon balm. Apples, pears, orchard fruits. Caramel malt. A touch of wax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Moderate, quite mild. Mostly malt. Apple and pear danishes. Chai latte, predominantly cinnamon. Swirls of caramel. Milk chocolate and hazelnuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Classic profile, one imagines. Wish it was bottled at a higher proof, texture lets it down. 82/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/glen-flagler-5.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="glen-flagler" /><summary type="html">Silent distillery. Bottling apparently for the Italian market. Parafilmed and everything!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bowmore 2001 Hunter Laing 13 years 58.5% (refill hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-bowmore-2001-hunter-laing.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bowmore 2001 Hunter Laing 13 years 58.5% (refill hogshead)" /><published>2021-05-09T21:30:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:30:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/bowmore-2001-hunter-laing</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-bowmore-2001-hunter-laing.html">&lt;p&gt;OB Bowmore gets a bit of a bad rep. Luckily this is not OB. Bottled for Shinanoya in Japan under Hunter Laing’s “Old Malt Cask” label.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Vegetal and fruity. Celery, carrot, mangoes. Fresh and grassy (no understatement here). Orchard fruits, tart, apples and pears. Waxy fruit. Scented, lightly perfumed candles. Here we go: some elegant peat. Mossy, heady stuff. Rosewater. With some water, forested: wet oak, mushrooms, flowers, flowing creeks. A bit new age: incense, and a drop of oil. Turkish delight and rosewater – clarity of these is impressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Grassy, mossy peat. Ash and soot. Honey, caramel malt. Very malt forward, lovely. Liquorice and other assorted sweets. Bright, lemon-lime acidity. A hint of bark, not unlike bitters. With water: lemon syrup and orange peel. Don’t forget the pith!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; A touch of smoke, but mainly vegetal peat. Light honey. Oats and rosewater. Very floral, malty. Scented candles. Hot and warming, quite long. Scented smoke throughout. With water, smokier and earthier. Turkish delight. Watermelon, rockmelon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Elegance is the first word that comes to mind. Woody, scented, malt-driven. The antithesis to your dime-a-dozen smoke bomb
Islay. I also love rosewater. 89/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/bowmore-2001-hl.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="bowmore" /><category term="hunter-laing" /><summary type="html">OB Bowmore gets a bit of a bad rep. Luckily this is not OB. Bottled for Shinanoya in Japan under Hunter Laing’s “Old Malt Cask” label.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Aultmore 2010 Infrequent Fliers 10 years 58.5% (refill barrel)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-aultmore-2010-awwc.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Aultmore 2010 Infrequent Fliers 10 years 58.5% (refill barrel)" /><published>2021-05-09T21:20:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:20:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/aultmore-2010-awwc</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-aultmore-2010-awwc.html">&lt;p&gt;One of Alistair Walker’s Infrequent Fliers – a relatively recent independent bottler. Now, picture a sunny day, a swim-in bar…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Tropical explosion. Pineapples and bananas. Pina colada. Pineapple chocolates. Honey and perfume. A little grassy, fresh. Some mint. Candied apples and vanilla. Malt. With water, some nectarines and white grapes shine through. Back to bananas! But those candy bananas?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Pina colada again. Creamy and spicy — chilli, cayenne. Pineapples, bananas, mangoes. Very tropical. Brown sugar syrup. With water, more malt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Mint. Dessicated coconut and pineapple juice. White chocolate and almonds. Bananas (again…). Caramel and a hint of cherries. Long. Warming. A touch of oak. With water, minty notes come to the fore, with some cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; If we’ve smoke bombs, peat bombs, sherry bombs, then this is a tropical bomb. Lovely malt. Impressive clarity. Pina colada, anyone? 88/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/aultmore-2010-awwc.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="aultmore" /><category term="awwc" /><summary type="html">One of Alistair Walker’s Infrequent Fliers – a relatively recent independent bottler. Now, picture a sunny day, a swim-in bar…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Highland Park 2006 Gordon &amp;amp; Macphail 14 years 58.5% (refill sherry puncheon)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-highland-park-2006-gm.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Highland Park 2006 Gordon &amp;amp; Macphail 14 years 58.5% (refill sherry puncheon)" /><published>2021-05-09T21:10:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T21:10:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/highland-park-2006-gm</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-05-09-highland-park-2006-gm.html">&lt;p&gt;A recent non-secret Orkney.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Gold.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Malt. Dried fruits and a whack of salinity. Mint and heavily iced cookies. Manuka honey and a bit of wood. Tropical fruits: bananas, mangoes. A touch of wax. Double coat Tim Tams and Milk chocolate digestives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Very malty, sweet caramel. Some woody, smoky peat. Milk chocolate. Black pepper. Very creamy, thick mouthfeel. Alcohol is well integrated. A few herbal, menthol notes in the background tying it all together. Some smoked desserts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Chocolate milk and smoke. Dried berries and coffee. Very malty! Quite long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Solid, orthodox, traditional HP. Sweet chocolate, coastal characteristics rounded by earthy peat. 87/100.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;img/highland-park-2006-gm.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;bottle shot&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="highland-park" /><category term="gordon-macphail" /><summary type="html">A recent non-secret Orkney.</summary></entry></feed>