<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-29T10:55:37+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Spirit Record</title><subtitle>Just here to drink.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Springbank (Longrow) 1994 North Star 25 years 48.5% (refill exbourbon hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-springbank-longrow-north-star.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Springbank (Longrow) 1994 North Star 25 years 48.5% (refill exbourbon hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-29T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/springbank-longrow-north-star</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-29-springbank-longrow-north-star.html">&lt;p&gt;Part of North Star’s recent Springbank lineup. Both Springbank and North Star are highly respected and popular, so as expected, it flew off the shelves…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light honey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; An immediate attack of banana, rockmelon, pawpaw, and star anise. Springbank funk: rubbery and herbal. Cookies and cream ice cream and stem ginger. Vegetal peat and a touch of smoke: smoked mushrooms. Vanilla and white chocolate. Pineapple. Incredible. Intoxicatingly fruity, herbal, and rubbery, as if it’s got a texture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Spicy. Hot chilies. So malty, with that rubbery Springbank character. Anise and caraway, lapsang souchong and watermelon.  Cherries and ripe bananas. Yoghurt and rosewater. Textured milk and floral notes. Oily. Complex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Regal peat, smoke and tires. Tropical fruits and black tea again. Dark chocolate. Moderately long but very warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; Technically flawless stuff. Ridiculous amounts of ripe tropical fruits. Regal peatsmoke and the classic rubbery Springbank character. One of the most complex, balanced drams out there. 94/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="springbank" /><category term="north-star" /><summary type="html">Part of North Star’s recent Springbank lineup. Both Springbank and North Star are highly respected and popular, so as expected, it flew off the shelves…</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linkwood 2007 Hidden Spirits 13 years 54.1% (refill exbourbon hogshead)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2007-hidden-spirits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linkwood 2007 Hidden Spirits 13 years 54.1% (refill exbourbon hogshead)" /><published>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/linkwood-2007-hidden-spirits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2007-hidden-spirits.html">&lt;p&gt;Linkwood is a distillery you don’t see often bottled by Diageo themselves. Fortunately it is a relatively common malt among independent bottlers. Here we’ve got one from Hidden Spirits, a small Italian independent bottler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Light straw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Rockmelon, flowers, caramel and basil. White wine: Viognier? Lemon candy. Fresh and grassy. A little stemmy – think an apple plus some greenery. Springtime. Whiffs of coconut and fresh marmalade on toast. Museli. As it sits the coconut gets stronger: lamingtons. Incredibly perfumed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Powerful stuff! Floral explosion. So bright and a little spicy – chilli heat. Lemons, bergamot, and more flowers. Into the malt. Thick: cookies and cake batter. Complements the acidity well. A little minerality, chalk. Interesting! Lightly honeyed and incredibly floral, woodsy – not oak, but a bit like a small overgrown garden. Orange peels. Something strongly alternative-medicinal: eucalyptus, tea tree oil. A little water emphasises these characters, plus a little pepper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Deeply warming and spicy. Floral. Hot honey and mulled wine: cinnamon, cloves. Ginger. Pawpaw and eucalyptus. Green apples and tropical fruits. Banana. Extremely long. Perhaps the warmest finish in recent memory. Gum leaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; This malt is insane. Unrepentantly distillate forward. Complex. Floral, citrusy, spice bomb. 91/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="linkwood" /><category term="hidden-spirits" /><summary type="html">Linkwood is a distillery you don’t see often bottled by Diageo themselves. Fortunately it is a relatively common malt among independent bottlers. Here we’ve got one from Hidden Spirits, a small Italian independent bottler.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Linkwood 2009 Single Malts of Scotland (Elixir) 10 years 48% (seven cask vatting)</title><link href="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2009-smos.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Linkwood 2009 Single Malts of Scotland (Elixir) 10 years 48% (seven cask vatting)" /><published>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</published><updated>2021-04-28T00:00:00+10:00</updated><id>http://spiritrecord.com/linkwood-2009-smos</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://spiritrecord.com/2021-04-28-linkwood-2009-smos.html">&lt;p&gt;Another Linkwood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Colour&lt;/strong&gt; Straw. Likely refill hogsheads for most of the vatting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nose&lt;/strong&gt; Floral and perfumed: reminds me a bit of an Armagnac. Honey, mead. Acidity: lemons and limes, white wine. Lemon peel. Lychee and unripe berries. Bready malt. A little herbal and woody. Green apples stewing away for a pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Palate&lt;/strong&gt; Acidic and floral. The Octomore of flowers. Buttery and thick, like a croissant. Tangerines, lemons, and limes, particularly the peels. Oily. Savoury and spicy malt to complement the flowers. It’s like some citrus jam on croissants absolutely covered in flowers. Drinks a little hotter than 48%. More malt, cream. Tea-like: earl grey with sugar. Eucalyptus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finish&lt;/strong&gt; Chilli peppers, more flowers and croissants. Textured milk and white chocolate. Intensely long and warming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Comments&lt;/strong&gt; A lovely floral dram. I’m really digging the croissants mixed with fresh acidity. Delicious everyday whisky. 86/100.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dominic</name></author><category term="reviews" /><category term="scotch" /><category term="linkwood" /><category term="elixir" /><summary type="html">Another Linkwood.</summary></entry></feed>